<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<language id="44">
<page id="17" title="Boardcomp. objects" descr="Quad line groups for ware factory pairs or twins (spoken by Boardcomputer)" voice="yes">
 <t id="96117">TIE Fighter</t>
 <t id="96118">The TIE Fighter was the Galactic Empire's most widely-used fighter throughout the Galactic Civil War. Cheap and lightly-armed, they are best deployed in large numbers.</t>
 <t id="96119">Venator Star Destroyer</t>
 <t id="96120">The Venator Star Destroyer was widely used during the Clone Wars by the Galactic Republic. This versitile ship comes armed with heavy turbolasers, shielding, and it can deploy a large compliment of fighters.</t>
 <t id="96121">TIE Interceptor</t>
 <t id="96122">The TIE Interceptor was introduced twoards the end of the Galactic Civil War to suit the Empire's need for a more nimble and versatile fighter able to properly rival those of the Rebel Alliance. It comes equiped with better manuverability, shields, and weapons than a standard TIE fighter.</t>
 <t id="96123">TIE Defender</t>
 <t id="96124">The TIE Defender was the Galactic Empire's most advanced heavy fighter ever produced. Engineered as a part of Grand Admiral Thrawn's new fighter initiative, it comes armed with eight weapons, heavy shields, bomber-class missiles, and the most firepower of any Imperial fighter. Despite all of this, the Empire decided to discontinue the project in favor of the Death Star.</t>
 <t id="96125">TIE SF Fighter</t>
 <t id="96126">The TIE/sf space superiority fighter was the First Order's take on the classic TIE Fighter of the Galactic Empire. Among improved weapons and shields, this fighter notably contains a rear-facing turret, providing the ship with extra versatility.</t>
 <t id="96127">Corellian Corvette</t>
 <t id="96128">The Corellian CR90 Corvette was used extensively by the Rebel Alliance during the Galactic Civil War. Armed with medium laser cannons and the ability to dock a fighter externally, this fast corvette is best suited for fighter screening and escorting larger ships in a fleet.</t>
 <t id="96129">TIE Interceptor Repair Ship</t>
 <t id="96130">This TIE Interceptor has been modified to perform repairs on other ships. It has no combat capabilities but can mount four repair lasers.</t>
 <t id="96131">Tartan Patrol Cruiser</t>
 <t id="96132">The Galactic Empire's Tartan Patrol Cruiser excells at fighter screening and light patrol duty. Unlike heavier imperial corvette designs, the Tartan cannot use medium weapons, instead utilizing a large array of light cannons.</t>
 <t id="96133">TIE Phantom</t>
 <t id="96134">The TIE Phantom was originally a rare prototype fighter of the Galactic Empire that had advanced cloaking technology. However, this particular model has been optimized for scouting duties and therefore does not contain a cloaking device.</t>
 <t id="96135">TIE Bomber</t>
 <t id="96136">Lightly armed, fragile, and slow for a ship of its size, the Galactic Empire's TIE Bomber is capable of launching practically any type of Imperial missile, and contains a large cargo bay to carry them.</t>
 <t id="96137">TIE Scimitar Bomber</t>
 <t id="96138">The Scimitar Assault Bomber was used in Grand Admiral Thrawn's campaign against the New Republic in place of the older TIE Bomber, and continued service into the Yuuzhan Vong War. This ship is faster and sturdier, and can also launch almost every type of Imperial missile.</t>
 <t id="96139">K-Wing Bomber</t>
 <t id="96140">The K-Wing heavy bomber was used by the New Republic to replace the older Y-Wing and B-Wing bomber craft due to its extra versatility. This ship is fast, heavily-armed, and capable of firing almost any type of Commonwealth missile.</t>
 <t id="96141">Gallofree Transport</t>
 <t id="96142">The Gallofree GR75 Transport was widely used by the Rebel Alliance during the Galactic Civil War. This freighter carried supplies, troops, and vehicles throughout rebel-controlled space to meet logistical needs.</t>
 <t id="96143">Droid Tri-Fighter</t>
 <t id="96144">Introduced late into the Clone Wars, the Droid Tri-Fighter was used to great effect by the Separatist Confederacy of Independant Systems. Like all droid fighters, it is both cheap to produce and easy to destroy. The Tri-Fighter is incredibly fast, and able to fire swarm missiles.</t>
 <t id="96145">Vulture Droid</t>
 <t id="96146">The Vulture Droid was the main droid starfighter of the Separatist CIS during the clone wars. Lightly armed and fragile, these fighters are best used in large quantities to overwhelm their opponents.</t>
 <t id="96417">Munificent Frigate</t>
 <t id="96418">The Munificent-class Star Frigate saw heavy use during the Clone Wars by the Separatists, making up the bulk of thier fleets. The Munificent suffers from poor hull strength and lack of weapons coverage, making them most effective when lined up and facing their targets. This ship can carry up to 4 fighters.</t>
 <t id="96419">Providence Dreadnought</t>
 <t id="96420">The Providence-class Dreadnought served in the Clone Wars as the flagship of many high-ranking Separatists. The ship itself doubles as a destroyer and a carrier capable of carrying many fighters.</t>
 <t id="96421">ARC-170</t>
 <t id="96422">The ARC-170 starfighter was used by the Galactic Republic during the Clone Wars. This heavy fighter contains heavy shielding, a durable hull, heavy lasers, and a rear turret. Its most notable shortfall is its lack of speed.</t>
 <t id="96423">Y-Wing BTL-B</t>
 <t id="96424">The BTL-B Y-Wing was the Galactic Republic's main bomber during the Clone Wars. While the ship is not nimble or fast, it is heavily armed and contains a turret for added protection. This ship can fire almost any type of commonwealth missile.</t>
 <t id="96425">Y-Wing BTL-B</t>
 <t id="96426">This Republic BTL-B Y-Wing has been captured by the pirates and modified to use the plasma burst generator.</t>
 <t id="96427">Hammerhead Corvette</t>
 <t id="96428">The Hammerhead Corvette was used by the Rebel Alliance during the early days of the Galactic Civil War. Converted from freighters, these ships were obsolete compared to the standard CR90 Corellian Corvette in nearly every aspect of performance, except for the Hammerhead's superior hull strength and larger cargo bay.</t>
 <t id="96429">E-Wing</t>
 <t id="96430">Developed by the New Republic, the E-Wing starfighter was built with well-rounded performance for a ship of its size. The fighter served alongside the X-Wing throughout the Yuuzhan Vong War and beyond.</t>
 <t id="96431">X-Wing R</t>
 <t id="96432">The iconic fighter of the Rebel Alliance and the factions that succeeded it, the X-Wing starfighter is a medium-sized ship with generally good performance for a ship of its size. Red variant.</t>
 <t id="96433">X-Wing B</t>
 <t id="96434">The iconic fighter of the Rebel Alliance and the factions that succeeded it, the X-Wing starfighter is a medium-sized ship with generally good performance for a ship of its size. Blue variant.</t>
 <t id="96435">X-Wing T-70</t>
 <t id="96436">The T-70 X-Wing was used by the Resistance to replace the old Rebel T-65 X-Wing fighter in its fight against the First Order. This newer model is faster, has greater hull and weapon strength, and a larger cargo bay. This ship has also been fitted with a rear-facing turret for added protection.</t>
 <t id="96437">V-Wing</t>
 <t id="96438">The V-Wing was used by the Galactic Republic twoards the end of the Clone Wars. This fighter was built for speed, and it lacks reliable durability as a result.</t>
 <t id="96439">B-Wing Bomber</t>
 <t id="96440">The B-Wing fighter/bomber was the largest and most heavy-hitting fighter ship in the Rebel Alliance fleet. Armed with a staggering 10 laser cannons, heavy shields, and a heavy missile payload, this ship's only notable weakness is its lack of manuverability. This ship can launch nearly any type of commonwealth missile.</t>
 <t id="96441">YT-2400</t>
 <t id="96442">The Corellian YT-2400 light freighter, while not possessing a massive cargo bay like slower, heavier freighters, is very fast and quite well-armed for a cargo ship. Used all throughout the galaxy, It excells at quickly freighting low-volume goods for quick profits, or instead using its speed to outrun the authorities. Rebel variant.</t>
 <t id="96443">YT-2400</t>
 <t id="96444">The Corellian YT-2400 light freighter, while not possessing a massive cargo bay like slower, heavier freighters, is very fast and quite well-armed for a cargo ship. Used all throughout the galaxy, It excells at quickly freighting low-volume goods for quick profits, or instead using its speed to outrun the authorities. Empire variant.</t>
 <t id="96445">YT-1300</t>
 <t id="96446">The Corellian YT-1300 light freighter is an older craft that began widespread use throughout the galaxy during the early days of the Galactic Empire. While not the fastest or most reliable, this ship is easily modifiable, with this particular model outfitted with dual quad turrets and heavy shields, giving the ship light combat capabilities. Rebel variant.</t>
 <t id="96447">YT-1300</t>
 <t id="96448">The Corellian YT-1300 light freighter is an older craft that began widespread use throughout the galaxy during the early days of the Galactic Empire. While not the fastest or most reliable, this ship is easily modifiable, with this particular model outfitted with dual quad turrets and heavy shields, giving the ship light combat capabilities. Empire variant.</t>
 <t id="96449">YT-1300 Falcon</t>
 <t id="96450">Heavily and illegally modified to suit the needs of pirates and smugglers, this Corellian YT-1300 light freighter boasts a port-mounted cockpit, increased firepower and combat capabilities, greater speed, and a slightly-increased cargo bay.</t>
 <t id="96451">Dynamic-Class Freighter</t>
 <t id="96452">This ship seems to have been abandoned for quite some time, and is not registered in the galactic holonet. Who knows how long it has been drifting through space? It does not share design traits with any known shipmaker in the galaxy, as this is likely an ancient design with unknown capabilities. Upon closer inspection of the mostly-garbled data on the onboard computers, the term &quot;Revan&quot; appears constantly, although there is no telling what that means.</t>
 <t id="96453">MC80 Liberty</t>
 <t id="96454">The MC80 Liberty-type Star Cruiser was developed by the Mon Calamari and used as the Rebel Alliance's main capital ship in the Galactic Civil war, and early on by the New Republic. While slightly lacking in firepower and hangar space compared to an Imperial Star Destroyer, the Liberty possesses superior shields and durability.</t>
 <t id="96455">X-Wing Repair Ship</t>
 <t id="96456">This X-Wing fighter has been modified to perform reapirs on other ships. It has no combat capabilities, but is able to mount four repair lasers.</t>
 <t id="96457">ETA-2 Jedi Starfighter</t>
 <t id="96458">The ETA-2 starfighter was used by the Jedi Knights late in the Clone Wars to replace the older Delta-7 starfighter. The ship itself is extremely small, nimble, and fragile, and unable to take a hit. The fighter instead relied on the Jedi pilot's force abilities to outmaneuver enemy laser fire and perform surgical strikes.</t>
 <t id="96459">Delta-7 Jedi Starfighter Y</t>
 <t id="96460">The Delta-7 Starfighter was used by the Jedi Knights throughout the Clone Wars. Lighter than any fighters used by the Republic, this ship was built for speed and it relied on the Jedi pilot's force abilities to avoid enemy fire. Yellow variant.</t>
 <t id="96461">Delta-7 Jedi Starfighter R</t>
 <t id="96462">The Delta-7 Starfighter was used by the Jedi Knights throughout the Clone Wars. Lighter than any fighters used by the Republic, this ship was built for speed and it relied on the Jedi pilot's force abilities to avoid enemy fire. Red variant.</t>
 <t id="96463">Delta-7 Jedi Starfighter G</t>
 <t id="96464">The Delta-7 Starfighter was used by the Jedi Knights throughout the Clone Wars. Lighter than any fighters used by the Republic, this ship was built for speed and it relied on the Jedi pilot's force abilities to avoid enemy fire. Green variant.</t>
 <t id="96465">Delta-7 Jedi Starfighter B</t>
 <t id="96466">The Delta-7 Starfighter was used by the Jedi Knights throughout the Clone Wars. Lighter than any fighters used by the Republic, this ship was built for speed and it relied on the Jedi pilot's force abilities to avoid enemy fire. Blue variant.</t>
 <t id="96467">Delta-7 Jedi Starfighter K</t>
 <t id="96468">The Delta-7 Starfighter was used by the Jedi Knights throughout the Clone Wars. Lighter than any fighters used by the Republic, this ship was built for speed and it relied on the Jedi pilot's force abilities to avoid enemy fire. Black variant.</t>
 <t id="96469">Delta-7 Jedi Starfighter R</t>
 <t id="96470">After the fall of the Jedi Order at the end of the Clone Wars, many Jedi ships and assets were stolen by pirates and scavangers. This Delta-7 has been modified by the pirates to use their Mass Driver weapon. Red variant.</t>
 <t id="96471">Delta-7 Jedi Starfighter Y</t>
 <t id="96472">After the fall of the Jedi Order at the end of the Clone Wars, many Jedi ships and assets were stolen by pirates and scavangers. This Delta-7 has been modified by the pirates to use their Mass Driver weapon. Yellow variant.</t>
 <t id="96473">BFF-1</t>
 <t id="96474">The BFF-1 Bulk Freighter was a common sight in the galaxy around the time of the Galactic Civil War. The ship is slow, but capable of carrying large quantities of freight.</t>
 <t id="96475">U-Wing</t>
 <t id="96476">The U-Wing was both a troop transport and a gunship used by the Rebel Alliance during the Galactic Civil War. The ship is fast enough to fly into dangerous situations and has moderate firepower in order to provide light support.</t>
 <t id="96477">Y-Wing Bomber</t>
 <t id="96478">The Y-Wing was the Rebel Alliance's most common bomber craft for attacking capital ships and stations. Much cheaper and simpler than the B-Wing and in service long before the advent of the K-Wing, this ship proved reliable enough despite its many flaws in speed and cargobay size. This ship can fire nearly any type of Commonwealth missile.</t>
 <t id="96479">MC80 Liberty</t>
 <t id="96480">This scaled-down version of the MC80 Liberty-type Starcruiser is a TL-class cargo hauler with a massive cargobay and large external docking ports, capable of docking up to TS-class freighters. While it can carry more fighters than any other TL, it comes completely unarmed, relying only on missiles for defense.\n</t>
 <t id="96481">Debug X-Wing</t>
 <t id="96482">This ship is for testing purposes only. You should not be able to obtain it in the regular game!</t>
 <t id="96483">Lambda Shuttle</t>
 <t id="96484">The Lambda Shuttle is a common ship used by the empire as a passanger shuttle for high-ranking imperial officials. As such, the ship lacks in combat and defensive capabilities.</t>
 <t id="96485">A-Wing</t>
 <t id="96486">The A-Wing Interceptor is among the smallest and fastest ships in the Rebel Alliance fleet. This ship is best suited for light combat and scouting duties.</t>
 <t id="96487">T-Wing</t>
 <t id="96488">The T-Wing Interceptor was a largely-flawed Rebel design from the Galactic Civil War. Slower and bulkier than an A-Wing, but with the same lack of firepower, this ship simply cannot compete with others in its class. The only potential draw to the T-Wing is its moderate cargobay size, which could potentially carry a decent quantity of advanced satelites.</t>
 <t id="96489">Recusant</t>
 <t id="96490">The Recusant Light Destroyer was a powerful warship in service of the Separatists during the Clone Wars. Unlike the smaller Munificent Frigate, the Recusant is able to win direct confrontations with Republic Venators thanks to its heavy lasers and excellent turret coverage.</t>
 <t id="96491">Z-95A</t>
 <t id="96492">Originally introduced during the Clone Wars, the Z-95 Headhunter was replaced by the X-Wing during the Galactic Civil War by the Rebel Alliance. The ship is an older fighter with slightly lacking stats, however the ship comes very cheap and is is a capable fighter in its own right. Unlike the X-Wing, however, this ship is too light to mount the powerful High Energy Plasma Thrower weapon.</t>
 <t id="96493">Corellian Gunship</t>
 <t id="96494">The Corellian DP20 Gunship is a corvette design focusing on speed, firepower, and shields. In addition to its deadly laser armaments, the ship is capable of using any type of commonwealth missile, including the Tomahawk Heavy Missile typically used by bombers. The DP20 can also launch boarding parties, making it popular among pirates and rebels.</t>
 <t id="96495">Corellian Gunship</t>
 <t id="96496">This Corellian DP20 Gunship has been in use by the pirates for its boarding and missile capabilities. It has also been modified to use pirate mass driver and plasma burst generator weapons.</t>
 <t id="96497">Old Republic Station</t>
 <t id="96498">These stations served as the galactic hub for both the Old Republic and the Sith Empire during ancient times. This restored replica station has been converted into an equipment dock for use in outfitting ships.</t>
 <t id="96499">X-70B Phantom</t>
 <t id="96500">The X-70B Phantom Prototype was an advanced ship used by only the most elite agents and sith among the ancient Sith Empire. Restored to work with modern systems, the ship is still capable of using many laser and missile types, despite appearing as a civilian luxury ship. The most notable feature of the ship, however, is its incredible manuverability for a ship of its size due to its engines containing ancient and unknown Sith technology.</t>
 <t id="96501">XS Freighter Y</t>
 <t id="96502">The XS Freighter was popular with smugglers during the ancient times of the Old Republic. This ship is a re-creation of the ancient design engineered to use modern weapons and equipment. Yellow variant.</t>
 <t id="96503">XS Freighter G</t>
 <t id="96504">The XS Freighter was popular with smugglers during the ancient times of the Old Republic. This ship is a re-creation of the ancient design engineered to use modern weapons and equipment. Grey variant.</t>
 <t id="96505">BT-7 Thunderclap</t>
 <t id="96506">The BT-7 Thunderclap is an ancient ship design dating back to the days of the Old Republic, where it was used by special forces in the Republic millitary. The ship has been refurbished to allow compatibility with modern weapons and equipment.</t>
 <t id="96507">D-5 Mantis</t>
 <t id="96508">The D-5 Mantis was a rare, ancient design popular with bonty hunters during the time of the Old Republic. This scrappy ship, while technically a freighter, is especially well-armed and capable of using missiles, much to the suprise of its vicitims.</t>
 <t id="96509">Slave 1</t>
 <t id="96510">This heavily-modified Firespray-31 starship is an attempted recreation of the infamous &quot;Slave 1&quot; ship belonging to Boba Fett, the legendary Mandalorian bounty hunter. This ship itself serves as both a fighter and a bomber, and is capable of firing nearly any type of Imperial or Commonwealth missile.</t>
 <t id="96511">Firespray-31</t>
 <t id="96512">While not as powerful as the infamous &quot;Slave 1&quot; owned and upgraded by the notorious bounty hunter Boba Fett, the base-model Firespray-31 is still a very dangerous ship used by criminals and pirates. It comes heavily-armed and is capable of using nearly any type of Imperial or Commonwealth missile.</t>
 <t id="96513">Kihraxz</t>
 <t id="96514">The Kihraxz Starfighter was used by the Black Sun Pirates during the time of the Galactic Empire. This nuisance comes equipped with standard M3 laser cannons and shields.</t>
 <t id="96515">VCX-100</t>
 <t id="96516">The VCX-100 Light Freighter was a Corellian freighter design with exceptional firepower and defense capabilities. The ship is also capable of docking two fighters for added support. Most famously, the &quot;Ghost&quot; used by the Rebellion was a Corellian VCX-100.</t>
 <t id="96517">YT-2000</t>
 <t id="96518">The Corellian YT-2000 Light Freighter is a direct improvement to the older YT-series models, coming equipped with heavier shields, firepower, and the ability to use some missiles. The ship's smaller size also grants it exceptional manuverability. New Republic variant.</t>
 <t id="96519">YT-2000</t>
 <t id="96520">The Corellian YT-2000 Light Freighter is a direct improvement to the older YT-series models, coming equipped with heavier shields, firepower, and the ability to use some missiles. The ship's smaller size also grants it exceptional manuverability. Imperial Remnant variant.</t>
 <t id="96521">LAAT</t>
 <t id="96522">The LAAT Hauler is a light freighter hauler, modified from the Republic's heavy LAAT Gunship used in the Clone Wars. Despite otherwise being nothing more than a cheap freighter, the ship retains its ability to fire some missiles, although not nearly of the same payload of an actual LAAT Gunship.</t>
 <t id="96523">LAAT Gunship</t>
 <t id="96524">The Republic's LAAT Gunship is an extremely versitile ship, able to perform many roles including a heavy gunship, a landing transport, and ground support for the Clone Army. In space, the ship acts as a very well-armed passenger shuttle.</t>
 <t id="96525">G9 Rigger</t>
 <t id="96526">The G9 Rigger Freighter is a cheap and outdated light freighter, with poor stats all around. By the time of the Clone Wars, only a few of these rusty ships remained in the galaxy.</t>
 <t id="96527">T-16 Skyhopper</t>
 <t id="96528">The T-16 is an old civilian craft, ususally used as a personal vehicle or extremely light freighter. The famed rebel Luke Skywalker's training shooting Tatooine Womp Rats in his T-16 Skyhopper was instrumental in the destruction of the first Death Star.</t>
 <t id="96529">Aurek Fighter</t>
 <t id="96530">This ancient starfighter dates back thousands of years to the Old Republic, where it was the primary fighter craft used in the Old Republic Fleet. Despite being advanced for its time, this restored model does not compete well with today's ship technology.</t>
 <t id="96531">Neutron Star Bulk Cruiser</t>
 <t id="96532">This large ship was used throughout the galaxy as a heavy load transporter, both for civilian freight or for millitary troops and supplies. The ship contains light laser defenses and limited docking capacity. New Republic variant.</t>
 <t id="96533">Neutron Star Bulk Cruiser</t>
 <t id="96534">This large ship was used throughout the galaxy as a heavy load transporter, both for civilian freight or for millitary troops and supplies. The ship contains light laser defenses and limited docking capacity. Imperial Remnant variant.</t>
 <t id="96535">YKL-37 Nova Courier</t>
 <t id="96536">The Gallofree YKL-37 Nova Courier was the last ship produced by Gallofree Yards before the company's bankruptcy in the early New Republic era. The ship classifies as a light corvette with a large cargobay, making it ideal for dangerous transportation jobs.</t>
 <t id="96537">YKL-37</t>
 <t id="96538">After the collapse of Gallofree Yards during the early New Republic Era, many of its assets were claimed by pirates and smugglers. This YKL-37 Nova Courier has been modified to use pirate weapons and mounts an extra shield.</t>
 <t id="96539">Gozanti C-ROC</t>
 <t id="96540">The Corellian C-ROC Gozanti Cruiser is a large, heavy freighter used throughout the galaxy. This ship is a major departure from the standard Gozanti Cruiser design, Leaving behind the heavy defenses to cut costs.</t>
 <t id="96541">Pelta</t>
 <t id="96542">The Pelta-Class Frigate was used by the Republic during the Clone Wars as a medical transport, supply ship, and blocade runner. While not containing the massive cargobay that other TL-class freighters have, the Pelta comes with extra shielding and defenses, making it more than capable of defending itself from smaller ships.</t>
 <t id="96543">Dreadnought Heavy Cruiser</t>
 <t id="96544">One of the most common capital ships in the galaxy, the Dreadnought Heavy Cruiser was also used by the Imperial Remnant. The ship's primary role in Imperial fleets was to provide supporting fire to the main Star Destroyers, overwhelming all opposition. Imperial Remnant variant.</t>
 <t id="96545">Dreadnought Heavy Cruiser</t>
 <t id="96546">Because the Dreadnought Heavy Cruiser was the galaxy's most common capital ship, even the Mandalorians had a few of their own. These models have been outfitted to equip Mandalorian weapons and even deploy boarding pods. Mandalorian variant.</t>
 <t id="96547">Nebulon-B Frigate</t>
 <t id="96548">The Nubulon-B Frigate is a light escort Frigate used by the Rebel Alliance for a variety of purposes. The ship also contains light docking capacity.</t>
 <t id="96549">DP-37 Frigate</t>
 <t id="96550">The DP-37 light carrier frigate is a common Corellian design often found in patrols and escort positions. It is a fast and light carrier able to provide close fighter support without being a big, slow target like the Quasar. New Republic variant.</t>
 <t id="96551">DP-37 Frigate</t>
 <t id="96552">The DP-37 light carrier frigate is a common Corellian design often found in patrols and escort positions. It is a fast and light carrier able to provide close fighter support without being a big, slow target like the Quasar. Pirate variant.</t>
 <t id="96553">DP-37 Frigate</t>
 <t id="96554">The DP-37 light carrier frigate is a common Corellian design often found in patrols and escort positions. It is a fast and light carrier able to provide close fighter support without being a big, slow target like the Quasar. Imperial Remnant variant.</t>
 <t id="96555">MC80 Independence</t>
 <t id="96556">The Independence variant of the powerful Mon Calamari MC-80 Cruiser is probably best-known for the Home One, Admiral Ackbar's flagship that played a large role in the Alliance victory at the Battle of Endor. As the most powerful ship in the Rebel Fleet, it is capable of carrying dozens of starfighters and comes with extremely heavy shielding.</t>
 <t id="96557">AEG-77 Vigo</t>
 <t id="96558">This Black Sun Pirate vessel is statistically similar to a light corvette, however also posessing the cargobay capacity of a light freighter. This allows it to serve as a convoy escort, dangerous space transport, or simply as a classic pirate ship for boarding and pillaging.</t>
 <t id="96559">Victory Star Destroyer</t>
 <t id="96560">The Imperial Victory-class Star Destroyer is a smaller variant of the iconic Imperial-class star destroyers, with a smaller hull and proportinal firepower and shields. While this ship is weaker than normal star destryoers, it is still a fully-capable M7 destroyer on its own.</t>
 <t id="96561">Skipray Blastboat</t>
 <t id="96562">The GAT-12 Skipray Blastboat is a ship developed by Mandalorian shipwrights, however it was most famously used by the criminal Zann Consortium before its collapse after the Battle for the Eclipse. While the ship's laser defenses are lackluster for a ship of its size, its bomber capabilities are its primary appeal. This ship can fire nearly any type of commonwealth missile.</t>
 <t id="96563">Skipray Blastboat</t>
 <t id="96564">This pirate Skipray Blastboat has been modified to use pirate weapons, although it still retains its deadly bomber missile capabilities.</t>
 <t id="96565">Starviper</t>
 <t id="96566">This unusual fighter was common among the criminal underworld, most notably with the Zann Consortium, where it served as the organization's main starfighter. The ship is also capable of using a large variety of lasers and missiles, but sadly not buzz droids.</t>
 <t id="96567">Marauder Cruiser</t>
 <t id="96568">The Rebel Alliance's Marauder Cruiser is a missile corvette, capable of launching heavy, long range missiles such as the tomahawk heavy missile and the hammer torpedo. The ship also comes with light laser defenses.</t>
 <t id="96569">Legacy Star Destroyer</t>
 <t id="96570">The Legacy-class Star Destroyer, only built in limited numbers, was a Republic capital ship that gave up the Venator's large hangars in exchange for more firepower and shields. The Legacy-class also mounts two heavy, foward-facing ion cannons on either side.</t>
 <t id="96571">Assault Frigate MK1</t>
 <t id="96572">Used by the New Republic, the Assault Frigate MK1 is a stripped-down and heaviy modified Dreadnought Heavy Cruiser. While its speed is superior to the original Dreadnought, the Assault Frigate MK1's poor durability holds it back from competing on the same level.</t>
 <t id="96573">Assault Frigate MK2</t>
 <t id="96574">The Assault Frigate MK2 was introduced by the Rebel Alliance and continued service into the era of the New Republic. This heavy capital ship has heavy firepower as well as light docking capacity.</t>
 <t id="96575">A-Wing RZ-2 R</t>
 <t id="96576">The newest A-Wing model, this ship was used by the Resistance in its fight against the First Order. It has many improvements over the original A-Wing including speed, cargo capacity, and weapon energy. Red variant.</t>
 <t id="96577">A-Wing RZ-2 B</t>
 <t id="96578">The newest A-Wing model, this ship was used by the Resistance in its fight against the First Order. It has many improvements over the original A-Wing including speed, cargo capacity, and weapon energy. Blue variant.</t>
 <t id="96579">Gozanti</t>
 <t id="96580">The Gozanti Super Freighter was built with defense in mind, despite being a bulky heavy freighter. The ship comes equipped wtih corvette-grade shields, good turret coverage, and the ability to fire missiles. New Republic variant.</t>
 <t id="96581">Gozanti</t>
 <t id="96582">The Gozanti Super Freighter was built with defense in mind, despite being a bulky heavy freighter. The ship comes equipped wtih corvette-grade shields, good turret coverage, and the ability to fire missiles. Imperial variant.</t>
 <t id="96583">Nebula Star Destroyer</t>
 <t id="96584">The powerful Nebula Star Destroyer, despite its imperial appearance, was created by the New Republic to replace its aging Mon Calamari cruisers in a fleet modernization effort. This cutting edge destroyer has superior shields, firepower, speed, and hangar capacity to nearly all other destroyers in the galaxy.</t>
 <t id="96585">YT-1760</t>
 <t id="96586">The Corellian YT-1760 is on the lower-end of YT-series freighters, coming with the smallest cargobay of them all. The ship also does not have enough power to properly fire its weapons for sustained periods of time, and is very lightly shielded.</t>
 <t id="96587">Y8</t>
 <t id="96588">The Corellian Y8 Miner is a ship designed for mining asteroids and found throughout the entire galaxy. As a mining ship, it is slow and defenseless, and really can't be used for any other purpose.</t>
 <t id="96589">MC75 Cruiser</t>
 <t id="96590">The MC75 Star Cruiser was most famously used by the Rebel Alliance in the Battle of Scarif, where Admiral Raddus's flagship, the Profundity, was a MC75. The ship classifies as a light destroyer/carrier hybrid, being the master of neither role.</t>
 <t id="96591">MC40a Frigate</t>
 <t id="96592">The MC40a Frigate is a medium Mon Calamari warship used by the New Republic and the Rebellion before it. The ship has a small hangar, but its most notable feature is its above-average shields, standard for any Mon Calamari design.</t>
 <t id="96593">MC30c Frigate</t>
 <t id="96594">The MC30c Frigate was used by the Rebellion and the New Republic after it. This ship is a M7M missile Frigate, relying on long-range torpedo attacks to devastate capital ships. Despite its offensive power, the ship is lightly defended and instead uses its exceptional speed to avoid danger.</t>
 <t id="96595">MC90 Cruiser</t>
 <t id="96596">The most powerful Mon Calamari Cruiser in the New Republic fleet, the MC90 was built specifically to outclass Imperial Star Destroyers. Hangar capacity, shields, and weapons are all superior to those of its predecessors, as this is the first Mon Calamari Cruiser specifically designed for combat.</t>
 <t id="96597">Braha'tok Gunship</t>
 <t id="96598">The Dornean Braha'tok Gunship is a light corvette built for the sole purpose of starfighter defense. The Rebel Alliance used a few of these ships in the Battle of Scarif and the Battle of Endor, despite it being far inferior to the CR90 and DP20 corvettes.</t>
 <t id="96599">Quasar-Fire Carrier</t>
 <t id="96600">Rebel variant. This Quasar-Fire Carrier has been repurposed and modified by the rebellion. Shields and weapons have been stripped down from the standard imperial model in favor of greater speed.</t>
 <t id="96601">Quasar-Fire Carrier</t>
 <t id="96602">Imperial variant. The Imperial Quasar-Fire Carrier is a light fighter carrier with a moderate hangar capacity and light defenses. Being bulky and slow, it is not ideal as an attack cruiser, instead excelling as a light carrier.</t>
 <t id="96603">Star Destroyer I-1</t>
 <t id="96604">The Imperial 1-Class Star Destroyer was the Empire's main destroyer used to project power across the galaxy. In addition to its superior firepower, the I-1 also doubles as a carrier.</t>
 <t id="96605">Star Destroyer I-2</t>
 <t id="96606">The Imperial 2-Class Star Destroyer is among the most devastating capital ships in the galaxy, thanks to its unmatched firepower. Unlike the Imperial-1, the Imperial-2 specializes in capital weapons, and cannot use lighter anti-fighter weapons. The I-2 also sacrifices hangar capacity in favor of greater shields and hull strength.</t>
 <t id="96607">TIE Advanced</t>
 <t id="96608">This imperial prototype is most famed for being the personal fighter of Darth Vader himself. The fighter is defined by superior shields and manuverability to those of standard imperial fighters.</t>
 <t id="96609">Gozanti</t>
 <t id="96610">The Gozanti Vanguard was used as an imperial light patrol craft, capable of carrying up to four fighters. The ship boasts light defenses of its own, and also serves as a freighter.</t>
 <t id="96611">Vigil Corvette</t>
 <t id="96612">The imperial Vigil Corvette, despite its size and class, was designed to fit a destroyer role. As such, it is slower and bulkier than a standard patrol craft, with superior shields and weapons. This ship also contains external fighter docking capacity.</t>
 <t id="96613">Interdictor</t>
 <t id="96614">The Empire's Interdictor Destroyers possessed the unique ability to pull enemy ships out of hyperspace and prevent jumps using its gravity well generators. However, this model has had its gravity wells removed, leaving a light destroyer best suited for fighter screening, as it lacks the firepower of a standard Victory Star Destroyer.</t>
 <t id="96615">Strike Cruiser</t>
 <t id="96616">The Imperial Strike-class meduim cruiser is an imperial medium fire-support cruiser. This ship contains heavy foward firepower and boarding capabilities, however its lackluster turret coverage render it defenseless if surrounded.</t>
 <t id="96617">Strike Cruiser</t>
 <t id="96618">Captured Imperial Strike Cruisers are in high demand among pirates, thanks to their firepower and boarding capabilities. This cruiser has been modified by the pirates to use pirate weapons and have greater speed in order to chase down targets, at the cost of reduced weapon energy.</t>
 <t id="96619">Lambda</t>
 <t id="96620">The imperial transport is used to carry supplies, troops, and vehicles throughout the Empire. It also serves as a planetary landing craft.</t>
 <t id="96621">Lambda Sentinel</t>
 <t id="96622">This makeshift transport has been scrapped together out of the remains of a Lambda Sentinel and a massive cargo crate where the ship's mid-section used to be, resulting in the original ship's main shield generator and weapon generator being cut out. While the crate has a much larger capacity than a standard Sentinel, the added weight drastically reduces the ship's speed.</t>
 <t id="96623">Lambda Sentinel</t>
 <t id="96624">This makeshift transport is comprised of a scrapped Lambda Sentinel frame used to carry a large cargo container. The ship has been stripped of its weapons and some of its shield generators. While the crate holds more cargo than the standard Sentinel, the added weight results in the ship being slowed down.</t>
 <t id="96625">Imperial Escort Carrier</t>
 <t id="96626">The Imperial Escort Carrier, used only by Imperial Special Forces, is very fast and contains light hangar space. This ship is designed for boarding, able to quickly get in close and launch Imperial Storm Commandos.</t>
 <t id="96627">Imperial Light Corvette</t>
 <t id="96628">The Imperial Light Corvette was designed by the Empire for carryng a single squadron of fighters, making this ship ideal for patrol duty or supporting roles. The ship itself has very poor firepower and shields, instead relying on its squadron for protection.</t>
 <t id="96629">Imperial Light Cruiser</t>
 <t id="96630">The Arquitens-class light cruiser was carried over from the Clone Wars into Imperial service, while most other Republic ships, such as the Venator Star Destroyers, were retired. The Imperial Light Cruiser is fast and well-armed, and excells at patrol duty.</t>
 <t id="96631">Resurgent Star Destroyer</t>
 <t id="96632">The Resurgent-class was deployed by the First Order, bringing more firepower, size, and shields than the old Imperial-class star destoyers. The front of the ship also serves as a massive fighter hangar bay.</t>
 <t id="96633">Rogue Shadow</t>
 <t id="96634">The Rogue Shadow was the personal transport of Sith Assassin Starkiller, the secret apprentice of Darth Vader. The ship itself compares to a high-end corvette, with above-average speed.</t>
 <t id="96635">Gladiator Star Destroyer</t>
 <t id="96636">Unlike the heavy Imperial-class star destroyers, the Gladiator-class was only moderately armed and instead specialized for carrier duties. The ship is also capable of utilizing more advanced torpedo types, such as the Imperial Ghoul and Shadow torpedos.</t>
 <t id="96637">Zeta-class shuttle</t>
 <t id="96638">The Imperial Zeta-class cargo shuttle is a slow and bulky freighter with above-average shields and lasers. They were most notably used to transport Kyber Crystals used in the construction of the Death Star, and a stolen Zeta-class was used to transport the Rebel group Rogue One to the surface of Scarif to steal the Death Star plans.</t>
 <t id="96639">Acclamator</t>
 <t id="96640">The Acclamator Hauler, beginning service in the Clone Wars, was orignially used to transport entire batallions of clone troopers around the galaxy. During the Imperial Era, the ship did not see much service other than heavy transport and infrastructre duties.</t>
 <t id="96641">Gladiator Star Destroyer</t>
 <t id="96652">This Gladiator Star Destroyer has been captured by pirates and outfitted with pirate weapons and boarding systems in order to be used for piracy. Many of these pirate modifications have resulted in a loss of engine speed and shields. Pirate fuel from the black market also makes the ship's engine exhaust glow a blood red.</t>
 <t id="96653">Acclamator</t>
 <t id="96654">The Acclamator Assault Ship, carried over from the Clone Wars, is hardly able to compete with modern ship designs. The ship can use Imperial Shadow missiles and houses a squadron of fighters, however its most glaring issue is exceptionally weak shields for a ship of its size. Empire variant.</t>
 <t id="96655">Acclamator</t>
 <t id="96656">The Republic Acclamator is a large starship used to transport Clone Army forces around the galaxy. While usually protected by a fleet of Venator Star Destroyers, the Acclamator is still capable of holding its own in medium engagements, especially thanks to its ability to use Commonwealth flail barrage missiles. Republic variant.</t>
 <t id="96657">Raider Corvette</t>
 <t id="96658">The Imperial Raider Corvette is a high-end corvette, heavily armed with heavy weapons, unlike most corvettes which use medium or light weapons. The ship has superior shields, speed, and boarding capabilities, making it the starship of choice for elite Imperial special forces.</t>
 <t id="96659">TIE Hunter</t>
 <t id="96660">Used by the Storm Commandos, the Imperial TIE Hunter was designed to counter the X-wing starfighter of the Rebel Alliance. The ship performs better than the standard TIE Interceptor but is more expensive as a result.</t>
 <t id="96661">Sith Scimitar</t>
 <t id="96662">The Sith Scimitar, also known as the Sith Infiltrator, was the personal starship of Darth Maul before the start of the Clone Wars. The ship resembles a very heavy fighter, and is of highly experimental design. Its ability to mount medium weapons gives it a massive advantage in combat.</t>
 <t id="96663">XG-1 Star Wing</t>
 <t id="96664">The Alpha-class XG-1 Star Wing was an early Imperial fighter design, which was quickly scrapped in favor of the much cheaper TIE fighter line. The remaining ships became popular all over the galaxy after leaving millitary service. The ship is very bulky for a starfighter, however it contains heavy shields and a large cargobay capable of carrying XL-class containers.</t>
 <t id="96665">Lancer Frigate</t>
 <t id="96666">The Lancer Frigate was developed by the Imperial Remnant in an attempt to cover the Empire's major starfighter weaknesses. This ship bridges the gap between capital Frigates and light patrol craft.</t>
 <t id="96667">Guardian Mantis</t>
 <t id="96668">The Guardian Mantis is the personal starship of Naboo mercenary Vana Sage, who flew attacks against the Trade Federation. The ship is essentially a medium starfighter.</t>
 <t id="96669">C-9979 Transport</t>
 <t id="96670">The C-9979 Landing Craft is a Separatist Army heavy transport capable of carrying droid ground forces. While slow, its large cargobay makes the ship useful by civilians as a heavy freighter.</t>
 <t id="96671">Praetorian Cruiser</t>
 <t id="96672">The Praetorian Frigate was the predecessor to the Old Republic Hammerhead Cruiser. This replica of the ancient ship design has been modernized to light corvette standards, although it still fails to compete with most ships.</t>
 <t id="96673">PLY-3000</t>
 <t id="96674">The Personal Luxury Yaught 3000 is a luxury transport used by wealthy individuals and criminals throughout the galaxy. Most famously, Lando Calrissian and Mara Jade were both owners of PLY-3000 starships. Republic variant.</t>
 <t id="96675">PLY-3000</t>
 <t id="96676">The Personal Luxury Yaught 3000 is a luxury transport used by wealthy individuals and criminals throughout the galaxy. Most famously, Lando Calrissian and Mara Jade were both owners of PLY-3000 starships. New Republic variant.</t>
 <t id="96677">Defender Corvette R</t>
 <t id="96678">The Defender-class corvette was a ship of the ancient Jedi Order, and was standard-issue for all ranks of Jedi Knights and Jedi Consulars. This relic of the Old Republic era was never quite capable for combat, as its Jedi owners often neglected to upgrade or maintain their ships. As such, it cannot hold its own against any modern starship design, but may see use as a transport. Red variant.</t>
 <t id="96679">Royal Starship</t>
 <t id="96680">The J-Type 327 Nubian Royal Starship was used by Naboo Royalty during the Clone Wars Era. The ship itself is faster than average passenger transports.</t>
 <t id="96681">V-19 Torrent</t>
 <t id="96682">Used in the early Clone Wars, this Republic starfighter's speed and mobility make up for its large profile and wear shielding.</t>
 <t id="96683">Arquitens Cruiser</t>
 <t id="96684">The Arquitens Light Cruiser was used by the Republic and Jedi Order for escort duties and boarding operations. The ship's speed and manuverability pair well with its boarding capabilities, making it suitable for clone commando teams.</t>
 <t id="96685">CR-20</t>
 <t id="96686">The Corellian CR-20 Transport was originally used as a troop transport by the Republic before the Acclamator Assault Ship. The CR-20 is a heavy bulk freighter with heavy defenses for a transport, as it contains excellent turret coverage. Republic variant.</t>
 <t id="96687">CR-20</t>
 <t id="96688">The Corellian CR-20 Transport was originally used as a troop transport by the Republic before the Acclamator Assault Ship. The CR-20 is a heavy bulk freighter with heavy defenses for a transport, as it contains excellent turret coverage. Mandalorian variant.</t>
 <t id="96689">Z-95T</t>
 <t id="96690">The pirate Z-95T variant is the only Z-95 Headhunter model to feature four lasers, as most models contain only two. As the ship was never designed to support so many weapons, the pirates achieved this at the cost of reduced shields and speed.</t>
 <t id="96691">Z-95 AF-4</t>
 <t id="96692">The Z-95 AF-4 starfighter was used by the Republic in the later years of the Clone Wars. The ship was deployed alongside the heavier and slower ARC-170, with the Z-95 having superior speed while retaining heavy shielding.</t>
 <t id="96693">Foray Corvette</t>
 <t id="96694">The Foray Corvette served along with the Hammerhead Cruiser in the Old Republic Navy as a capital ship. Mass-produced during the ancient times, it is not uncommon to find modernized Forays in the galaxy today among ship collectors and historians.</t>
 <t id="96695">Kimogila M12-L R</t>
 <t id="96696">The Mandalorian-built M12-L Kimogila heavy fighter has heavy shielding and weapons, and is an excellent all-around fighter. Red variant.</t>
 <t id="96697">Kimogila M12-L G</t>
 <t id="96698">The Mandalorian-built M12-L Kimogila heavy fighter has heavy shielding and weapons, and is an excellent all-around fighter. Green variant.</t>
 <t id="96699">Kimogila M12-L</t>
 <t id="96700">The M12-L Kimogila, despite being of Mandalorian design, was one of the main fighters used by the Hutts. The Kimogila is a very heavy fighter with heavy firepower and shields, and has been modified by the pirates to use many different weapon types.</t>
 <t id="96701">Scyk M3-A</t>
 <t id="96702">The Mandalorian M3-A Scyk Fighter is a lightly-armed and defended fighter craft, comparable to an Imperial TIE Fighter. The ship's speed and low cost make it ideal for scouting duties.</t>
 <t id="96703">Scyk M3-A</t>
 <t id="96704">The Mandalorian-built M3-A Scyk fighter was often used by Hutt and criminal organizations throughout the galaxy as a light fighter. This ship has been modified to use the pirate mass driver weapon.</t>
 <t id="96705">Dunelizard G1-M4-C R</t>
 <t id="96706">The G1-M4-C Dunelizard is a Mandalorian-built medium fighter. The ship was named after Tatooine Dune Lizards by the Hutts, who are most often associated with the ship. Red variant.</t>
 <t id="96707">Dunelizard G1-M4-C G</t>
 <t id="96708">The G1-M4-C Dunelizard is a Mandalorian-built medium fighter. The ship was named after Tatooine Dune Lizards by the Hutts, who are most often associated with the ship. Green variant.</t>
 <t id="96709">Dunelizard G1-M4-C</t>
 <t id="96710">This G1-M4-C Dunelizard fighter is in service to the Hutts, and used for all sorts of piracy and mercenary work. The Type-1 Dunelizard is a standard medium fighter except for its relatively poor shielding.</t>
 <t id="96711">Dunelizard G2-M4-C R</t>
 <t id="96712">The G2-M4-C Dunelizard, also known as the Type-II Dunelizard, is a slightly bulkier and enlarged model of the Mandalorian-built dunelizard fighter. This ship has enhanced hull strength and shields compared to the Type-I. Red variant.</t>
 <t id="96713">Dunelizard G2-M4-C G</t>
 <t id="96714">The G2-M4-C Dunelizard, also known as the Type-II Dunelizard, is a slightly bulkier and enlarged model of the Mandalorian-built dunelizard fighter. This ship has enhanced hull strength and shields compared to the Type-I. Green variant.</t>
 <t id="96715">Dunelizard G2-M4-C</t>
 <t id="96716">The G2-M4-C Type-II Dunelizard is a Hutt fighter containing slightly improved shields and armor to the Type-I. The added bulkiness results in the ship being slightly slower as a result.</t>
 <t id="96717">Action VI</t>
 <t id="96718">The Action VI Transport is a medium-sized bulk transport. The ship comes quite cheap for its cargobay class, however it contains no weapons and very dismal shielding, making it a prime target for pirates. Mandalorian variant.</t>
 <t id="96719">Action VI</t>
 <t id="96720">The Action VI Transport is a medium-sized bulk transport. The ship comes quite cheap for its cargobay class, however it contains no weapons and very dismal shielding, making it a prime target for pirates. Separatist variant.</t>
 <t id="96721">Defender Corvette W</t>
 <t id="96722">The Defender-class corvette was a ship of the ancient Jedi Order, and was standard-issue for all ranks of Jedi Knights and Jedi Consulars. This relic of the Old Republic era was never quite capable for combat, as its Jedi owners often neglected to upgrade or maintain their ships. As such, it cannot hold its own against any modern starship design, but may see use as a transport. White variant.</t>
 <t id="96723">Kom'rk</t>
 <t id="96724">The Kom'rk fighter, also known as the Mandalorian Gauntlet Fighter, was used by the Death Watch throughout the time of the Clone Wars, and later by Darth Maul's Shadow Collective. This heavy fighter's large profile is due to its ability to transport and deploy a small squad of Mandalorian warriors into combat.</t>
 <t id="96725">R-41 Starchaser</t>
 <t id="96726">The R-41 Starchaser fighter is an outdated design comparable to the Z-95 Headhunter, despite being a heavier-class ship. The R-41 is often used by pirate or mercenary groups despite its light shielding and poor manuverability.</t>
 <t id="96727">Fury</t>
 <t id="96728">The Fury-class Interceptor was one of the most common Sith Empire ships in the galaxy during the Old Republic era. Standard issue for the millions of Sith Warriors and Sith Inquisitors long before the rule of two, the ship saw heavy use as a personal transport.</t>
 <t id="96729">Leviathan</t>
 <t id="96730">The ancient Leviathan Cruiser is most famous for being the flagship of Darth Malak, who used a single Leviathan Cruiser to destroy the entire city planet of Taris, killing billions of citizens at once. Despite its place in galactic history, it is only able to mount medium weapons by modern standards and its disjointed hull shape gives it poor durability compared to modern ships.</t>
 <t id="96731">YV-100</t>
 <t id="96732">The Corellian YV-100 light freighter is a largely unremarkable and average ship design, common throughout the galaxy from the time of the Empire all the way up to the Yuuzhan Vong War. The YV-100 is cheaply made, with slightly below-average statistics compared to other common freighters.</t>
 <t id="96733">YV-666</t>
 <t id="96734">The YV-666 Freighter is an odd design, coming with heavy shields and even missile capabilities. The craft is also much more manuverable than typical freighters, making the ship combat-capable. The infamous Trandoshan bounty hunter Bossk piloted a YV-666 named the 'Hound's Tooth'. Separatist variant.</t>
 <t id="96735">YV-666</t>
 <t id="96736">The YV-666 Freighter is an odd design, coming with heavy shields and even missile capabilities. The craft is also much more manuverable than typical freighters, making the ship combat-capable. The infamous Trandoshan bounty hunter Bossk piloted a YV-666 named the 'Hound's Tooth'. Mandalorian variant.</t>
 <t id="96737">IRD-A</t>
 <t id="96738">The IRD-A Starfighter was mass-produced and used by the Corporate Sector Authority. Not intended for war, this ship mainly saw use by police and law enforcement and is therefore unable to be a direct competitor to most starfighters.</t>
 <t id="96739">IRD</t>
 <t id="96740">The Corporate Sector Authority's IRD Starfighter is fast, light, and designed for policing duties. This ship can mount many different types of laser cannons.</t>
 <t id="96741">MM-13</t>
 <t id="96742">The MandalMotors-built MM-13 transport is a common sight in Mandalorian space, transporting heavy loads with its above-average speed. The ship is also lightly armed with foward-facing cannons.</t>
 <t id="96743">OR Shuttle</t>
 <t id="96744">A common ship used by the Old Republic, the Old Republic Shuttle was most notably used to personally deliver all republic troopers to Ord Mantell at the start of their careers. The ship was also used to deliver countless expedition teams to the planet Athiss.</t>
 <t id="96745">Nu-Class Shuttle</t>
 <t id="96746">The Republic's Nu-Class Attack Shuttle was used extensively throughout the Clone Wars. Although serving the same purpose as the LAAT gunships, the Nu-Class came with heavier shields, making it too expensive for mass deployment. Instead, the Nu-Class was used to transport high-profile passengers such as senators or Jedi.</t>
 <t id="96747">Kandosii</t>
 <t id="96748">The Mandalorian Kandosii-Type Dreadnought is a capital ship destroyer/carrier hybrid. The design dates all the way back to the ancient Mandalorian Wars with the Old Republic and Jedi Order.</t>
 <t id="96749">Harrower</t>
 <t id="96750">The Harrower-Class Dreadnought was the main capital ship used by the Sith Empire during the ancient war with the Old Republic. Similar to a modern star destroyer, the ship is heavily armed and also has plentiful carrying capacity.</t>
 <t id="96751">Harrower</t>
 <t id="96752">This old Sith Harrower has been sitting abandoned for centuries before finally being discovered and restored by pirates. It has been repurposed to use pirate weapons.</t>
 <t id="96753">Valor</t>
 <t id="96754">The Valor-Class Cruiser was the largest ship in the Old Republic Fleet, capable of taking on Sith Harrower destroyers. The Valor has large hangar capacity, making it a capable carrier able to hold its own.</t>
 <t id="96755">N-1 Starfighter</t>
 <t id="96756">The N-1 Starfighter was used by the Naboo government during the time of the Clone Wars for patrol and escort duties. The ship is very fast and manuverable, able to evade heavy turbolasers with ease in the hands of a capable, adult pilot.</t>
 <t id="96757">Crusader Corvette</t>
 <t id="96758">Produced by Mandal Hypernautics, this deadly corvette gets its name from the old Mandalorian Crusaders that waged war on the Jedi Order. The ship excells against fighters, bombers, and even missiles with its anti-missile chaff. The ship was most infamously used by the Zann Consortium organization during and after the Galactic Civil War.</t>
 <t id="96759">Hammerhead Cruiser</t>
 <t id="96760">The Hammerhead-Class Cruiser was the primary capital ship used by the Old Republic Navy before the Valor entered service. Historically, the ship is known to be weak to swarms of smaller fighters but strong in numbers, with fleets able to destroy even the largest of stations. The most famous Hammerhead Cruiser was the Endar Spire, which was destroyed in an attack by Darth Bandon over Taris.</t>
 <t id="96761">HWK-290</t>
 <t id="96762">The HWK-290 is an old and unconventional freighter design, being exceptionally fast with a very small cargobay compared to other freighters. The most famous HWK-290 is the Moldy Crow, used by Kyle Katarn and Jan Ors for New Republic missions against the Imperial Remnant.</t>
 <t id="96763">Heraklon</t>
 <t id="96764">The Heraklon-class Transport is a heavy transport dating back to 4,000 BBY and the Old Republic. The ship is notoriously slow, but capable of carrying heavy loads rivaling modern super transporters.</t>
 <t id="96765">Consular Corvette</t>
 <t id="96766">This C-70 Consular Cruiser has been captured from Republic diplomats by pirates and outfitted with heavy destroyer weapons. The result is a fast and well-equipped corvette.</t>
 <t id="96767">Consular Cruiser</t>
 <t id="96768">In an age of galactic peace, the C-70 Consular Cruiser ferried Jedi and Republic diplomats across the galaxy. Of course, such valuable passengers use heavily-defended millitary transports now, so the C-70 does not see much use.</t>
 <t id="96769">Consular Corvette</t>
 <t id="96770">During the Clone Wars, the Republic upgraded many of their diplomatic Consular Cruisers into heavy corvettes, which were used to escort larger fleets of Venator Star Destroyers. These could also be used to great effect for outmaneuvering enemy capital ships, most notably during the Battle of Saleucami.</t>
 <t id="96771">Consular Courier</t>
 <t id="96772">This heavily-modified C-70 Consular has been converted into a freighter, stripping away weapons in exchange for cargo space. The Courier retains the craft's speed, making it a very efficient transport ship.</t>
 <t id="96773">Corellian Corvette</t>
 <t id="96774">This Corellian CR-90 Corvette is poorly-maintained by the pirates, resulting in reduced shield and engine performance than standard. This CR-90 has also been fitted with pirate weapons.</t>
 <t id="96775">Havoc</t>
 <t id="96776">Used by the infamous pirate Nym and mercenary Vana Sage, the Havoc starfighter is a nimble craft for its size, able to outmaneuver other M3-class fighters with ease.</t>
 <t id="96777">T-Wing</t>
 <t id="96778">This old T-Wing, while not useful for combat, has been outfitted by the Mining Guild for asteroid mining. Many of them working together can quickly clear out entire fields.</t>
 <t id="96779">TIE Scimitar</t>
 <t id="96780">The TIE Scimitar, with its large bomb bays and sturdy hull, works well in the role of a mining ship, among the best in the galaxy for its size.</t>
 <t id="96781">E-Wing</t>
 <t id="96782">Some of the E-Wings built by the New Republic that weren't deemed combat-capable or that were retired were converted and sold off as mining ships. While the ship performs well as a miner, it does not contain the manuverability and advanced equipment of its combat variant.</t>
 <t id="96783">C-9979</t>
 <t id="96784">The C9979 Droid Transport, due to its large carrying capacity and relative abundance, was often used by civilians after the Clone Wars as modified mining vessels. Its large cargobay allows it to mine a great quantity of asteroids before having to return to base.</t>
 <t id="96785">Havoc</t>
 <t id="96786">This Havoc starfighter has been modified for mining duties, taking advantage of the ship's large central cargobay for storing asteroid ore.</t>
 <t id="96787">Dunelizard G1-M4-C</t>
 <t id="96788">This Mandalorian Dunelizard fighter has been converted into a mining ship, able to use mining lasers for mobile mining.</t>
 <t id="96789">YV-100</t>
 <t id="96790">Corellian ships are not well-known as mining ships, but are often easily-modifiable. This YV-100 model has been modified for asteroid mining duties.</t>
 <t id="96791">TIE Fighter</t>
 <t id="96792">Used by the Mining Guild for security and for mining asteroids, these modified TIE Fighters can carry small quantities of ore and are thus best used in large quantities.</t>
 <t id="96793">Zeta-class</t>
 <t id="96794">Specialized for mining kyber crystals, these ships were used extensively in the early days of the Empire for a large project. These transports can mine asteroids for extended periods of time due to their large cargo-carrying capacity.</t>
 <t id="96795">Old Republic</t>
 <t id="96796">This Old Republic mining ship, while ancient in design, still functions well for basic asteroid mining and transport. Rennovated to use modern mining laser equipment.</t>
 <t id="96797">X-Wing T-65B</t>
 <t id="96798">The T-65B X-Wing starfighter is an updated version of the classic T-65 fighter used by the Rebel Alliance. In service of the New Republic Navy, the T-65B boasts impressive defensive and offensive capabilities, and comes slightly cheaper than the more advanced E-Wing.</t>
 <t id="96799">B-Wing Advanced</t>
 <t id="96800">Improved and modernized by the New Republic, this B-Wing heavy fighter/bomber is technologically superior to the ones used by the Rebel Alliance at the Battle of Endor. Heavier shields, greater speed and manuverability, and better durability all make this B-Wing a modern addition to the New Republic.</t>
 <t id="96801">DP-20 Advanced</t>
 <t id="96802">Modernized by the New Republic, this DP-20 Corellian Gunship focuses on firepower, shelding, and its advandced missile capabilities, and is now able to launch heavy Hammer Torpedos. These improvements, however, came at the cost of the ship's boarding capabilities.</t>
 <t id="96803">A-Wing Advanced</t>
 <t id="96804">In the New Republic Era, the A-Wing was overhauled from a light scouting ship into a proper interceptor, able to use fighter-grade PAC lasers and missiles. The ship retains its superior speed, ensuring its ability to chase down any target.</t>
 <t id="96805">TIE Fighter Advanced</t>
 <t id="96806">The common imperial TIE fighter continued service into the era of the Imperial Remnant, and saw slight upgrades over the years in the areas of speed, durability, and weapons energy.</t>
 <t id="96807">CR-25 Freighter</t>
 <t id="96808">The CR-25 Freighter was a ship used by the Rebel Alliance to carry vehicles and other equipment around the galaxy. The ship contains a large cargobay and a rear turret for light protection. Rebel variant.</t>
 <t id="96809">CR-25 Freighter</t>
 <t id="96810">The CR-25 freighter is a large cargo ship often found throughout the galaxy. While slow and unarmed, this ship can carry large quantities of freight reliably. Mandalorian variant.</t>
 <t id="96811">AA-9 Freighter</t>
 <t id="96812">The AA-9 Freighter is a large freight hauler with three powerful engines and it saw use duting the time of the Galactic Republic. Later models were outfitted for use as troop transports during the Clone Wars, but this particular model is designed for hauling freight.</t>
 <t id="96813">Allegiance Star Destroyer</t>
 <t id="96814">The Allegiance-class battlecruiser is one of the largest main-line Star Destroyers in the Imperial Navy. Unlike most Star Destroyers, the Allegiance focuses purely on raw firepower and overwhelming force, and doesn't contain any hangar bays. These ships were used heavily throughout Palpatine's Dark Empire starting around 10 ABY.</t>
 <t id="96815">Free-Virgillia</t>
 <t id="96816">The Free Virgillia-class Bunkerbuster CR-100 Frigate is a heavy corvette used by the Resistance in their fight against the First Order. While slow, this frigate boasts heavy firepower and shields along with many missile and bomb launchers.</t>
 <t id="96817">Raider Corvette</t>
 <t id="96818">This ship is a modified design of the Imperial Raider Corvette, designed by the New Republic after obtaining an Imperial variant belonging to defectors. The New Republic raider Corvette has greatly enhanced speed and manuverability.</t>
 <t id="96819">Vakbeor Frigate</t>
 <t id="96820">The Vakbeor Light Frigate is a hybrid design between the Nebulon Frigates of Kuat Drive Yards and the ships of Gallofree Yards. Modified for war by the Resistance, this ship is best suited for escort or patrol duties.</t>
 <t id="96821">XQ-2 Platform</t>
 <t id="96822">A common space station found throughout the Empire, the XQ-2 platform is a small outpost capable of docking multiple freighters, fighters, and medium-sized ships. These stations are well-suited as fuel outposts, mining bases, trade depots, and many other occupations.</t>
 <t id="96823">Tansarii Station</t>
 <t id="96824">Common throughout the lawless regions of the galaxy, these stations are used for all manner of pirate and smuggler activities. They usually contain docking capacity for small and medium-sized ships.</t>
 <t id="96825">Pelta</t>
 <t id="96826">Modified by Rebels as a makeshift warship, this Pelta has greatly increased weapon and engine power over the old Republic variants. Extra engines, installed on the unfolded back section of the ship, provide much-needed mobility for Rebel needs.</t>
 <t id="96827">StarFortress</t>
 <t id="96828">The MG-100 StarFortress SF-17 is a heavy bomber craft with a massive payload capable of destroying an entire capital ship on its own. However the ship itself is slow, poorly shielded, and very poorly defended with only light turrets for protection.</t>
 <t id="96829">Zakuul Dropship</t>
 <t id="96830">In the ancient era of the Old Republic, this shuttle was used by the Zakuul Eternal Empire. It is fast and moderately armed, although it is quite small, with limited passenger capacity.</t>
 <t id="96831">Carrack</t>
 <t id="96832">The Imperial Carrack-class Light Cruiser is a light escort frigate armed with SSC flak cannons. These ships were mass-produced by the Empire to project power across the galaxy and partol areas where a full Star Destroyer wasn't necessary.</t>
 <t id="96833">Carrack</t>
 <t id="96834">This alternate configuration of an Imperial Carrack Cruiser replaces the flak capabilities of the ship with heavy capital weapons. Able to contend with ships much larger than itself, a large group of upgraded Carracks can easily bring down large capital ships.</t>
 <t id="96835">Quadjumper</t>
 <t id="96836">The TUG-b13 Quadjumper is a cheap ship designed to haul other ships around using magnetic clamps. It is capable of hauling fighters around for fuel, repairs, and/or salvage.</t>
 <t id="96837">Quadjumper</t>
 <t id="96838">Outfitted for mining rather than tugging other ships through space, this Quadjumper model uses its powerful thrusters to travel at speeds much higher than other mining vessels, although its cargo hold is quite small.</t>
 <t id="96839">V-Wing Airspeeder</t>
 <t id="96840">The V-Wing Airspeeder is an atmospheric craft designed by the New Republic to be used on planets, were they can operate much cheaper than costly starfighters. While uncommon, this particular model has been outfitted with the proper engines and equipment such that it can traverse space.</t>
 <t id="96841">Secutor Star Destroyer</t>
 <t id="96842">The Secutor Star Destroyer was a massive carrier prominent during the Dark Empire period, capable of fielding an enormous amount of starfighters. The massive internal bays of this ship are also sufficent enough to carry and deploy stations.</t>
 <t id="96843">Victory Missile Destroyer</t>
 <t id="96844">This Victory Star Destroyer variant is specialized for missile launching capabilities, containing many lannch tubes on either side of the ship. It has less conventional laser firepower than a standard Victory Star Destroyer, however.</t>
 <t id="96845">CR-90 Repair Ship</t>
 <t id="96846">This long-lost and heavily-modified Corellian Corvette has been stripped of its standard weapons in favor of repair lasers.</t>
 <t id="96847">Gozanti Repair Ship</t>
 <t id="96848">This unique Gozanti Freighter has been experimentally modified with repair lasers rather than standard weapons.</t>
 <t id="96849">Rebel Starbase V</t>
 <t id="96850">A large space station designed by the Rebel Alliance and upgraded in stages, this starbase acts as a staging ground and equipment hub for rebel fleets. It is capable of accomodating many shipsof all sizes.</t>
 <t id="96851">YV-929</t>
 <t id="96852">The YV-929, commonly known as the &quot;flying brick&quot;, is a heavily armored freighter designed to hold its own against pirate raids. With corvette-grade shielding and armor, the ship is not as reliant on escorts as more average transports.</t>
 <t id="96853">Longhorn</t>
 <t id="96854">The Separatist Longhorn corvette is a light partol ship able to be operated by a smaller droid crew than the larger Munificent Frigate. Thus, the Longhorn is suited for light patrol duty and escorting capital ships. However, this ship was not widely produced throughout the Clone Wars and did not see much action on the front lines.</t>
 <t id="96855">Hutt Cruiser</t>
 <t id="96856">The Hutt Cruiser is a medium-sized missile frigate, notorious for boarding and piracy operations. They can also be found protecting vital systems in Hutt space.</t>
 <t id="96857">Sheathipede</t>
 <t id="96858">The Neimoidian-designed Sheathipede shuttle is a small and fast transport used throughout the Confederacy for various purposes. It is lightly armed and shielded.</t>
 <t id="96859">Sheathipede</t>
 <t id="96860">A light Neimoidian freighter used for small cargo shipments. Although later versions were used extensively by the Separatist navy during the Clone Wars, this model is a common civilian transport.</t>
 <t id="96861">Rihkxyrk</t>
 <t id="96862">The Black Sun's Rihkxyrk fighter is a heavy intercepor, similar in size and funciton to the X-Wing starfighter. This ship saw heavy use across the galaxy during the galactic civil war, as it was widely available to the highest bidder in most circumstances.</t>
 <t id="96863">Maxillipede</t>
 <t id="96864">The Maxillipede shuttle is a heavier and more durable than the Sheathipede, and as a result it did not see as much use as the cheaper Sheathipede shuttle during the Clone Wars.</t>
 <t id="96865">Umbaran Fighter</t>
 <t id="96866">Built and designed by the Umbarans, this unique fighter craft boasts advanced shields and firepower, making it a much-needed balance to the cheap droid starfighters used primarily by the Separatist Navy.</t>
 <t id="96867">Separatist Supply Station</t>
 <t id="96868">A stationary supply ship, this station is used as an orbital forward operating base by the Separatist Navy. It's large hangars are capable of holding countless fighters, while it has limited external docking capacities for larger ships.</t>
 <t id="96869">StarFortress</t>
 <t id="96870">A mining variant of the StarFortress bomber, this ship uses its large bomb bay to store ore and minerals mined from asteroids. While the ship's mining lasers aren't nearly as powerful as its competition, it can mine for a long time before having to drop off its freight.</t>
 <t id="96871">Paladin Corvette Bomber</t>
 <t id="96872">Having long served the Jedi Order, the Paladin-class dates back to the Old Republic era. One of these ships, The Crucible, was used traditionally by the Jedi Order to transport younglings to and from Ilum during kyber crystal rituals. While the ship is a capable missile platform, it almost never saw combat under Jedi command.</t>
 <t id="96873">Paladin Corvette</t>
 <t id="96874">Having long served the Jedi Order, the Paladin-class dates back to the Old Republic era. One of these ships, The Crucible, was used traditionally by the Jedi Order to transport younglings to and from Ilum during kyber crystal rituals. Due to its importance to the Jedi Order, the ship is quite well-armed, however in practice the Jedi avoided conflict when possible.</t>
 <t id="96875">Sith Fighter</t>
 <t id="96876">A small interceptor used in mass quantities during the Jedi Civil War, this fighter is an ancient design that is comparable to the modern TIE Fighter in function.</t>
 <t id="96877">Starhopper HH-87</t>
 <t id="96878">The HH-87 Starhopper was used by both the Hutts and the Zygerrian Slave Empire during the Clone Wars. It is a light fighter with an exceptional cargobay, allowing for long-range jumps and patrols.</t>
 <t id="96879">Zenith</t>
 <t id="96880">The Zenith Criuser is an Old Republic-Era battleship meant to provide heavy firepower where the Valor-class could not. The sentinel variant sacrifices speed for greater durability and shields.</t>
 <t id="96881">Zenith</t>
 <t id="96882">The Zenith Criuser is an Old Republic-Era battleship meant to provide heavy firepower where the Valor-class could not. The raider variant has exceptional speed for a ship of its size, at the cost of lower shield strength.</t>
 <t id="96883">Umbaran Cruiser</t>
 <t id="96884">The Umbaran Cruiser was a ship designed by the Umbaran Militia to aid the Separatist Navy and defend the planet Umbara against Republic invasion. The ship largely sees use today as a heavy transporter, helping with CIS logistical needs.</t>
 <t id="96885">IPV-1</t>
 <t id="96886">The &quot;Imperial Patrol Vehicle&quot;, despite being a precursor to the Tartan Patrol Cruiser for the Empire, is best known for its nefarious usage by the Black Sun Pirates. The IPV-1 is a very light patrol corvette, able to provide light anti-fighter screening.</t>
 <t id="96887">Mandalorian Starbase V</t>
 <t id="96888">A large Mandalorian-designed space dock, this station serves as a large orbital supply and equipment platform. It is capable of servicing ships of all sizes as well as serving as a center of trade and commerce. The Zann Consortium infamously used this model of station to project their influence across the galaxy.</t>
 <t id="96889">Keldabe</t>
 <t id="96890">Named after the capital city of Mandalore, Keldabe Battleships are the pride of the Mandalorian people. These formidable ships outclass both Imperial Star Destroyers and the standard Mon Calamari MC-80 with heavy shields, hull durability, and weapon power.</t>
 <t id="96891">Arrow Corvette</t>
 <t id="96892">The Imperial Arrow Corvette is a rare ship used sparingly by the Imperial Navy for light missile support. The ship contains two large missile launchers used for fighter screening, although the ship is still capable of using heavy torpedoes.</t>
 <t id="96893">Subjugator</t>
 <t id="96894">The most powerful Separatist warship ever built, the Subjugator-class is best known for the Malevolence, which waged many successful campaigns against the Republic before finally being destroyed at the hands of Anakin Skywalker during the Clone Wars. The Subjugator is large enough to need an internal railway network, and its sheer mass makes it very hard to destroy, even once its shields are down.</t>
 <t id="96895">Medical Station</t>
 <t id="96896">The Republic Haven-class medical stations were used as central hospitals for the large amount of Clone Troopers wounded during the Clone Wars. Despite their strategic importance, these stations were often hidden rather than defended, making them easy targts for Separatist fleets.</t>
 <t id="96897">F</t>
 <t id="96898">This Xenon freighter ship is a rare sight among recorded Xenon activity. These ships generally avoid areas of space with biological populations, and they are speculated to be used to transport raw materials from terraformed planets used to construct the vast Xenon armadas that threaten the X-Universe.</t>
 <t id="96899">H</t>
 <t id="96900">This Xenon frigate is extremely dangerous, and was reported to have missile launch capabilities. A relatively new Xenon design, it appears to be an evolution for Xenon fleet tactics, able to provide chaff and missile support for other Xenon craft.</t>
 <t id="96901">Corellian Destroyer</t>
 <t id="96902">These ships are light destroyers known for their powerful engines and exceptional speed, They also contain a very small forward target profile, making them excellent for heavy hit and run operations. The ship also contains light docking capacity for fighters.</t>
 <t id="96903">MC50 Carrier</t>
 <t id="96904">The Mon Calamari MC50 is a heavy carrier with a well-protected hangar located at the rear of the ship. The hangar's position makes it slow to launch fighters into battle, however this ship is more than capable of holding out on its own while deploying its fighters.</t>
 <t id="96905">Nebulon-A Frigate</t>
 <t id="96906">While never entering mass-produciton like the B and C class variants, the Nebulon-A light frigate saw light usage by the New Republic after the Galactic Civil War. Its lack of heavy firepower and survivability resulted in it being largely ignored by the major powers in the galaxy.</t>
 <t id="96907">Sith B-28 Bomber</t>
 <t id="96908">The ancient Sith used this ship, known as the B-28 Extinction Bomber. It was used heavily in the sacking of Coruscant and other ancient battles. This modern-day replica was created using Imperial technology and updated to use modern lasers and missiles.</t>
 <t id="96909">Atin Corvette</t>
 <t id="96910">A bulky corvette used to transport beskar ore to Mandalore from its moon Concordia, the Atin is durable and has above-average cargo capacity among corvettes. It has less firepower than the dedicated assault Crusader Corvettes.</t>
 <t id="96911">Raven PT-7</t>
 <t id="96912">A modern replica of the ancient Raven PT-7 starfighter used by the Old Republic. The raider variant is the faster version, although with less firepower.</t>
 <t id="96913">Raven PT-7</t>
 <t id="96914">A modern replica of the ancient Raven PT-7 starfighter used by the Old Republic. The vanguard variant sacrifices speed for extra firepower.</t>
 <t id="96915">Lucrehulk</t>
 <t id="96916">This enormous station, while technically a ship, serves many purposes in the CIS navy. Able to service an enormous amount of ships and act as a carrier, the Lucrehulk is often the logistical backbone of Droid Army deployments throughout the galaxy. This staiton has double the shield recharge rate than others in SWLU.</t>
 <t id="96917">MC85 Cruiser</t>
 <t id="96918">Very fast for its size, the MC85 cruiser is a heavy battle carrier capable of outclassing all but the biggest star destroyers. High shield durability and a large fighter compliment allow the MC85 to be very well defended against enemy fleets. No MC85 ever really got to use its abilities to their full potential, as the last cruiser in the New Republic fleet was embarrassingly destroyed without being able to fight back due to insufficient crew, in a slow and anti-climatic chase while it ran out of fuel.</t>
 <t id="96919">Bothan Assault Frigate</t>
 <t id="96920">The Bothan Assault Frigate is a medium frigate with hangar space for one squadron along with exceptional hull durability. These were used in limited numbers by the New Republic Navy.</t>
 <t id="96921">Shield Gate</t>
 <t id="96922">Oh heavily-defended Imperial planets, shield gates like these were used to serve as entry points through a planetary shield. This allowed the Imperial defenses to control and monitor all traffic in and out of the planet. When not used to gate a planetary shield, the station serves as a space equipment dock.</t>
 <t id="96923">Ton-Falk</t>
 <t id="96924">The Ton-Falk escort carrier is a large transport with enormous hangar capacity for fighters. While not heavily-armed on its own, the ship's fighters greatly make up for its own deficiencies.</t>
 <t id="96925">Broadside</t>
 <t id="96926">The Imperial Broadside cruiser was designed for the sole purpose of being a heavy missile platform. With 8 missile launchers, a single broadside cruiser can provide heavy fire support over a long range.</t>
 <t id="96927">Sith Interceptor</t>
 <t id="96928">The Mark-VI Supremacy fighter is an ancient starfighter dating back to the Sith Empire. While not much is known about its history, it appears to be an unremarkable light fighter. Sentinel variant.</t>
 <t id="96929">Sith Interceptor</t>
 <t id="96930">The Mark-VI Supremacy fighter is an ancient starfighter dating back to the Sith Empire. While not much is known about its history, it appears to be an unremarkable light fighter. Raider variant.</t>
 <t id="96931">Sith Scout</t>
 <t id="96932">This ancient starfighter was once known as the S-13 Sting, and dates back to the times of the Sith Empire. Not much is known about the history of these ships, although it still functions today as an outdated scout ship.</t>
 <t id="96933">Twintail X-38</t>
 <t id="96934">The successor to the X-wing line of fighters, the X-38 Twintail fighter was the primary fighter of the New Jedi Order. Shields, weapons, and just about all aspects of these ships have been improved from the days of the X-wing.</t>
 <t id="96935">GX1 Shuttle</t>
 <t id="96936">The GX1 Short Hauler, produced by Lantillian Shipwrights, is a passenger shuttle commonly found in Imperial space providing interplanetary transport services. TP variant.</t>
 <t id="96937">GX1 Short Hauler</t>
 <t id="96938">This GX1 Short Hauler has been configured for cargo hauling rather than passengers. These ships are commonly found throughout Republic and Imperial space. TS variant.</t>
 <t id="96939">GX1 Phoenix</t>
 <t id="96940">The GX1 Phoenix variant is a high-end diplomatic shuttle used by the Galactic Republic. It is much better-equipped than the civilian variants.</t>
 <t id="96941">YV-865 Aurore</t>
 <t id="96942">This bulky freighter was a common sight throughout the Zygerrian Slave Kingdom and other uncivilized areas of the galaxy around the time of the clone wars. These ships are often found carrying any matter of shady cargo from exotic creatures, spice, slaves, and/or stolen goods.</t>
 <t id="96943">IPV-2C Stealth Corvette</t>
 <t id="96944">Originally equipped with a prototpe cloaking device, this experimental ship was quickly discontinued from Republic service and the cloaking technology was removed. The oddly-shaped ship itself is still a nimble torpedo platform however.</t>
 <t id="96945">Gage</t>
 <t id="96946">The Gage-class hauler is a transport variant of the Terminus-class destroyer used by the ancient Sith Empire. It has a moderate TL-class cargo capacity although its armor and shields are better than average among transports. Some have been boarded and stolen by the Mandalorians and the Old Republic.</t>
 <t id="96947">Terminus</t>
 <t id="96948">The Terminus-class is a light capital ship dating back to the ancient Sith Empire. Although roughly equal in strength to an Old Republic Hammerhead-class, the Terminus is more flexible with its greater turret coverage.</t>
 <t id="96949">Valor Station</t>
 <t id="96950">This massive Republic space station served as a strategic operations center for Republic Navy ventures across the galaxy. Many high-ranking officers and Jedi are often based on these stations to command the war effort.</t>
 <t id="96951">Flying Camera</t>
 <t id="96952">If you somehow managed to get this, please report it as a bug!</t>
</page>
</language>
