<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<language id="44">

	<page id="350037" title="Encyclopedia Texts" descr="0" voice="no">
		<t id="62">Mayhem Help</t>
		<t id="63">Logistics</t> <!-- News -->
		<t id="64">Management</t> <!-- History -->
		<t id="65">Expansion</t> <!-- Information -->
		<t id="66">Miscellaneous</t> <!-- Stories -->
	</page>

	<page id="9974" title="Mayhem Encyclopedia Custom Articles">

		<!-- Logistics -->
		<t id="1">Sanctuaries And MLCC Docks</t>
		<t id="2">Sanctuaries are your main stations. They serve as local headquarters and also as factories with their ability to build ships, weapons, missiles and shields. They are crucial in your development, because they represent the only way you have to build stations and ships.\n\nSanctuaries do not work magically. People live inside and work together to manufacture everything you need. In exchange, you must provide them with food if you do not want them to starve to death. Each food has a different consumption rate, as you can see in the Food and Perks tab. People can work on multiple projects at the same time, but then the workload is shared between the tasks. For instance, if you have 100 people working on both a missile and a laser project, 50 people will work on the missile, and the 50 others on the laser. This rule can be bypassed with the Perk \033OOptimal parallel tasks\033X.\n\nSanctuaries are no more than advanced Docks. You can also build two MLCC Docks: the McCallum and the Starliner docks. MLCC will not be described here as it is a pretty powerful feature of Litcube's Universe. For more information on that subject, please read the online LU wiki.</t>
		<t id="3">Crafting And Specialization</t>
		<t id="4">Crafting is one of the most important features of Mayhem. Ships, stations, shields, weapons and equipment can be crafted with various resources that you can all produce by building factories in your sectors. In Mayhem, Saturn Complex Hubs and Vanilla Complex have been deactivated, but the costs of many things have been modified to keep the game balanced.\n\nAll crafting costs are based on the average price of the product you're trying to make. For instance, 1 Aurora missile costs 292 Energy Cells, 2 Quantum Tubes and 41 Warheads, but like every other product, there's also a time cost, also based on the average price. 1 Aurora missile has a project size of 1,295, meaning that at every tick, the amount of population is added to the project. For a standard 100 populated Sanctuary, it will then take about 13 ticks to finish the project. If you have another project being worked on - a station for instance - only half the population will work on the missile. Note that the Perk \033OOptimal parallel tasks\033X removes this penalty.\n\nEach Sanctuary has its own specialization levels in different areas. The more projects you complete in a specific area \(ship, laser, missile or shield\) the better you become at it. This bonus can go from 0% to 30%, and up to 50% with the appropriate Perks. That means that both resource and time costs will be reduced by this percentage.\n\nCancelling a project will always give you back the resources you invested.</t>
		<t id="5">Agents And Traders 1</t>
		<t id="6">Running an empire is about delegation and automation. To help you in the management of your empire, you have five main agents: Station Agents \(SA\), Dock Agents \(DA\), Freighters, Couriers and Universal Traders \(UT\). The most important change from Litcube's Universe concerns the logistics of your Sanctuaries. Instead of the Dockware Manager, a new system written from scratch gives you full control over your Dock Agents. These agents, unlike the other ones, have been drastically modified and they are the only ones to be affected by the logistics system. This new logistics system is based on jobs. A job is made of various settings:\n\n\033OTask\033X: can be either Acquire or Distribute. Acquire consists of loading or buying wares to bring them back to the Sanctuary. Distribute consists of taking wares from the Sanctuary and either sell or unload them.\n\033OWare\033X: the ware you want to either acquire or distribute.\n\033OMinimum / Maximum wares\033X: if you select Acquire, the Maximum wares is the amount of stock at which your agents will stop acquiring more wares. If you select Distribute, the Minimum wares is the amount of stock below which your agents will stop the distribution. \033GIf the specified condition is not met, the DA will ignore \033Gthe job.\n\033ODestination / Source\033X: can be Factories In Sector, Sanctuary or Trade. Factories In Sector makes your agents browsing all factories in the specified sector to look for opportunities: either bring products to the Sanctuary if you selected Acquire, or bring resources to the factories if you selected Distribute. Sanctuary limits the exchange to a specific Sanctuary or Dock. Trade makes the DA look for NPC sellers if you select Acquire, or NPC buyers if you select Distribute. You can then select a maximum price to buy or a minimum price to sell. Note that searching for a trading partner takes some time. This time can be reduced by equipping either a Best Buys Locator for Acquire operations or a Best Selling Price Locator for Distribute operations.\n\033OCargo Load\033X: you can either select full cargo, or custom cargo. Full cargo means that the DA will always load at its maximum capacity / availability. Custom cargo means that you have to specify a number of wares the DA must load at each run. This choice is important in early game, when you don't have much money. For instance, Microchips are very expensive, and you rarely want your agents to buy a full cargo of them... If you set "Wait for cargo load" to Yes, the DA will await for the station to have the specified number of wares that you specified, i.e. either a full cargo or a custom amount. It will not load anything before.\n\033OMaximum Ships\033X: that is the maximum number of ships you want working on that job. It's important to note here that when you select Distribute, your agents, on their way back, will not be considered being on any job. It's intended, as it can increase your productivity and avoid idling ships.\n\033OPriority\033X: all Dock Agents will browse the list of available jobs by order of priority. If two jobs have the same priority, they will be looked at the same way you can see them listed in the Directory tab. Having your jobs properly prioritized can make a real difference between a good and a poor logistics management. Note that all DA are constantly checking the job board, even when they are waiting for trading partners or valid thresholds.\n\033OPause\033X: paused jobs are ignored by your agents.\n\033OTimeout\033X: if a DA is waiting on a job and the specified number of seconds has passed, then the DA will go through all other jobs, respecting their timeout as well. All timeouts are reset when the DA accepts a job or finishes browsing the job list. Note that a timeout of 0 will always make the DA wait on its current job.\n\033OOpportune deliveries\033X: the DA will provide the station he's planned to go to with the resources it needs. This option is only available to Acquire jobs, with Factories In Sector as destination. This option respects the import threshold of the destination, and the export threshold of the Sanctuary. Opportune deliveries are synchronized with local jobs.</t>
		<t id="7">Agents And Traders 2</t>
		<t id="8">All stations and Sanctuaries have export and import thresholds. For stations, it's expressed in percentage. For Sanctuaries, it's expressed in number of wares, that you can configure in the Thresholds tab of the Logistics menu.\n\n\033OExport threshold\033X: if the stock is above this value, the ware can be exported to SA and DA.\n\033OImport threshold\033X: if the stock is below this value, the ware can be imported from SA and DA.\n\n\033GThese thresholds will not invalidate a job\033X, meaning that an on-job ship will await for optimal conditions and it will not go to a lower-priority job. The same rule applies if the ship does not find a trading partner or if the targeted station has locally paused DA and SA. This rule can be bypassed with the Timeout setting.\n\nA paused station will be ignored by the DA. If all valid stations are paused, the DA will wait for one of them to unpause.\n\nDock Agents set their own Fuel resupply quantity based on the Maximum jumps specified in the Sanctuary. They respect this value when the source is set to Trade. The refueling process is automatic. Also know that Dock Agents have a dedicated blacklist for sectors in which they have been attacked. They will avoid these sectors or any sector you manually add through your Personal Console in the appropriate section. Blacklisted sectors are only removed when you manually do it.\n\nCouriers have not been modified. Freighters are a bit optimized and Universal Traders come from the MK3 Improvement Reloaded Reloaded mod \(meaning they are lot smarter than the vanilla ones\). Sector Traders do not exist anymore. Universal Traders are now restricted to a maximum range that depends on their experience level \(see pilot name\) and also on their homebase trade jumps, if they have one. Universal Traders will prioritize your stations that are "open to your traders". Station Agents have been modified to always prioritize your factories and Sanctuaries, whether it's for buying \(fetching\) or selling \(delivering\). Note that Station Agents require the Station Agent Software, but the Dock Agents don't.</t>
		
		<!-- Management -->
		<t id="1001">Research And Blueprints</t>
		<t id="1002">The easiest way to acquire ships is to craft them with resources. However, to do that, you must first scan the ship data to have access to its blueprint, listed in all Research stations. Scanning data requires a Data Scanner that you have in your ship by default, and the assignment of the associated hotkey. But that's not all. Scanning a ship can be a bit tricky. You have to lower its shield to a certain point, then wait a moment for the scan to finish. During this time, the ship will attack you. Make sure to not go too far from it and to keep its shields at minimum.\n\nResearch stations are where your virtual scientists are working on unlocking the ship blueprints that become available in your Sanctuaries. Several Research stations can work on the same project. Their efficiency depends on their sector statistics, as well as their chance to have a major breakthrough leading to a very high income of research points. Note that each project can be interrupted and resumed at any time. Research stations do not depend on Sanctuary population.\n\nShip data can also be acquired through the Diplomacy menu or during Expeditions with your marines.\n\nOn your own ships, there is an additional command to scan their data, wherever you are. It can be useful if you forgot to scan them before.\n\nResearch stations also allow you to improve your marines. For more information, see the Expansion -> Marines: Improvements section.</t>
		<t id="1003">Perks</t>
		<t id="1004">Each perk is available right from the start of your game, but you are limited to 4 Perks per Sanctuary. This limit can be increased by declaring permanent war to one of the other factions, with the perk \033OAdjacency perk bonus\033X or with one of the Ascension rewards.\n\n\033OAdjacency perk bonus\033X: each adjacent Sanctuary receives one more maximum perk.\n\033OCheaper stations\033X: all stations are 50% cheaper.\n\033OComplex: Ship Components blueprint\033X: allows the Sanctuary to build a complex that contains a Chip Plant, a Computer Plant and a Quantum Tube Fab.\n\033OElectromagnetic pulse\033X: allows the Sanctuary to trigger an EMP that destroys every shield of every ship in the sector. It requires a large amount of Energy Cells and has a long recharge rate.\n\033OExtra engine tuning\033X: adds 2 engine tuning and 2 rudder optimization points over the maximum to all ships produced in the Sanctuary. The exact amount of speed added by these points depends on the ship.\n\033OFaster research\033X: the Research station in the sector works 50% faster.\n\033OFree insurance\033X: all your ships can be freely insured. You must advance in the main story to unlock the insurance feature.\n\033OJedi Temple blueprint\033X: allows the Sanctuary to build a Jedi Temple. The temple increases all sector statistics. You must advance in the Jedi story to reveal this perk.\n\033OHigh amplitude data scanner\033X: allows the Sanctuary to automatically scan the ship data of every ship with low shields in the sector.\n\033OIncreased maximum specialization levels\033X: each ship, laser, shield and missile maximum specialization level is increased from 30% to 50%. You can only select this perk if one of the manufacture perk \(or the Ship hangar\), has been unlocked.\n\033OLaser / Missile / Shield manufacture\033X: unlocks the corresponding production bay.\n\033OMarine barracks\033X: unlocks the possibility of hiring marines, designing their equipment and sending them into rifts.\n\033ONo food consumption\033X: people will naturally grow without food and they will never starve.\n\033OOCV station scanner\033X: scans all nearby sectors and reveal OCV stations if any. Effective range: 3 sectors. You must advance in the OCV story to reveal this perk.\n\033OOptimal parallel tasks\033X: allows to work on different projects without having production penalties.\n\033ORecycling infrastructure\033X: unlocks the recycling bay.\n\033OReduced OCV and invasions strength\033X: if an OCV wave targets the sector, the attacking fleet will be randomly reduced by approximately 25%. Same for invasions launched by other factions, but with an increased factor of 33%.\n\033OResupply drone\033X: the Sanctuary will send a drone to resupply all ships in the sector, including ships in carriers. The export threshold is respected.\n\033OShip hangar\033X: unlocks the ship hangar, the ship manufacture and the repair bay.\n\033OSkilled marines\033X: new marines come with better skills. You must unlock the Marine barracks before selecting this perk.\n\033OSolar panels\033X: the Sanctuary will regularly produce Energy-Cells from the sector's suns.\n\033OTax\033X: the Sanctuary will gain hourly money from local tax. The amount is based on the number of people.\n\nAll Perks on any Sanctuary are \033RNON-REFUNDABLE\033X. They cannot be reset.</t>
		<t id="1005">Relations And Diplomacy</t>
		<t id="1006">At any time in the Ministry of War screen, you can see the relations between all factions. Those are very hectic: they will vary throughout the game. Be sure to consult the Race Relations screen before engaging a ship.\n\n\033GFriendly\033X: cannot be invaded. Killing a ship in one of its friend's sector will get you a reputation penalty.\n\033WNeutral\033X: can be invaded. Police can still chase you if you kill a neutral faction ship in their sectors, but you won't lose any reputation.\n\033RFoe\033X: at least one invasion or defensive operation is in progress. You will get a reputation reward if you kill sector owner's foes.\n\nSeveral diplomatic actions can be taken through the Diplomacy menu. They are mostly self-explanatory and can be pretty powerful. Subjugation, for instance, makes a race do a complete stop in their progression: all their shipyards are destroyed and they do not rebuild their ships. You also get maximum reputation. Subjugation requires that the targeted race owns less than 4 sectors.\nNote that the amount of credits needed for a faction to launch an invasion depends on its race. This is how Mayhem makes factions more or less aggressive.\n\nIf you "Buy shipyards information", you will be able to see the budget of each shipyard and have a better understanding of their progress. It also gives the possibility to display invasion warning message for each of them. If you don't own shipyards information, a "CONFIDENTIAL" warning is displayed.\n\nDeclaring a permanent war to one of the other factions is irreversible. It will allow you to select one more Perk for each Sanctuary, but your reputation will drastically decrease. You can have a permanent war against two factions maximum. While in permanent war, most diplomatic actions are forbidden.\n\nReaching rank 10 with a faction makes all diplomatic actions free for this faction.</t>
		<t id="1007">Companies And Missions</t>
		<t id="1008">Companies are minor factions. Their main interest is to offer you missions of variable difficulty. These missions are only available for a time and they do not require you to accept them directly.\n\n\033GExecute\033X:  kill an astronaut.\n\033GConquer\033X: conquer a sector in the name of an other empire.\n\033GDefend\033X: destroy invading ships to defend a specific sector.\n\033GBreak\033X: destroy several M6s by piloting one of the ships manufactured by a specific race.\n\033GWeaken\033X: destroy a Solar Power Plant.\n\033GDestroy\033X: destroy an M7.\n\033GRescue\033X: save hostages and bring them back to a safe station. Note that the access to the station where they are kept is not always open to you.\n\033GBuy\033X: buy a ship docked at a specific station.\n\033GRob\033X: destroy a TS transporting a lot of money.\n\033GCollect\033X: destroy a miner transporting a Green crystal.\n\033GScan\033X: scan some asteroids.\n\nCompanies have only a few ships roaming the universe. They will loot flying wares and capture bailed ships.</t>
		
		<!-- Expansion -->
		<t id="2001">Sectors And Conquest</t>
		<t id="2002">Each sector in Mayhem has random statistics:\n\n\033WMaximum people\033X: the maximum amount of people you can have in a Sanctuary.\n\033WResearch rate\033X: how fast research points are generated.\n\033WBreakthrough\033X: a chance to receive extra research points at once.\n\033WSupport\033X: the maximum number of factories you can build. Note that all sectors are limited to 1 Dock, 1 Research station and 4 Orbital Weapons Platforms.\n\nAll these statistics are displayed in the Ministry of War screen.\n\nKnowing these statistics and the fact that other factions only invade sectors that are adjacent to theirs, you must plan your strategy before expanding your empire.\n\nTo conquer a sector you do not own, or to manage a sector you own, just hit the "Claim / Manage a sector" hotkey or use the Personal Console. You'll see that it's possible to capture a sector for another faction or to abandon one of your sectors.</t>
		<t id="2003">OCV And Orbital Weapons Platforms</t>
		<t id="2004">To protect your sectors from invaders, you can build some Orbital Weapons Platforms, or OWP. Because they are recognized as ships by the game, you must equip them after you placed them, with a ship equipped with a Transporter Device, through the "Advanced -> Freight exchange" menu. Also, turrets must be set up before they can fire. Don't forget to give a command to the OWP itself as well, like "Attack All Enemies", otherwise the main front turrets won't fire.\nTo prevent exploits, all wares you transfer to OWPs that are not shields, lasers or missiles will be automatically ejected.\n\nOWPs cannot be relocated, but you can use the self-destruct command in the Additional Ship Commands menu to retrieve 1 OWP slot.\n\nOrbital Weapons Platforms are a good idea when it comes to fight against the OCV.\n\nThe OCV is the main threat of the game. They launch invasions against your sectors on a regular basis. The next OCV invasion is displayed at the top of the Ministry of War screen. Fortunately, the invasion countdown only starts when you become a threat.\n\nThe OCV ships can come from everywhere and they will attack one of your sector every day. Note that OWPs are often a top-priority target for the OCV ships.\n\nIt is strongly recommended to NOT exceed Threat 5 before the first OCV invasion. Don't forget that your Threat is evaluated at the moment of the invasion, meaning that if it increases after the incoming message revealing the composition of the OCV fleet, this same fleet will be stronger.\n\nIf you're playing the Vagrant gamestart, the OCV is deactivated. You can also manually deactivate this feature by editing the "t-file". See Game Customization in the Miscellaneous section for more information.</t>
		<t id="2005">Dynamic War And Invasions</t>
		<t id="2006">The first goal of Mayhem is to implement a dynamic war, meaning that every faction can conquer other sectors. It's important to understand how it works.\n\nWhen you start a new game, shipyards are randomly spawned across the galaxy. You can dock to these shipyards to repair or sell your ships, but they mostly serve as headquarters for their owner and you cannot buy ships from them. Regularly, they will spawn standard vanilla ships, but also Battle Group ships. Those are the ones used to invade and defend their sectors.\n\nInvasions cost money. All shipyards are independent: when they have enough money to launch an invasion, they will do so. The target is always randomly chosen, and the amount of money needed to attack depends on the faction. The more expensive is an invasion, the less chance a faction has to conquer a new sector.\n\nSome sectors cannot be conquered. They are called "safe sectors". All factions do not conquer sectors the same way. Almost all factions, including the Old Republic and the Sith, and you, wage "dirty" wars. In a dirty war, factions destroy all stations. If they succeed, they conquer the sector.\n\nPirates act differently. They have their own score and they increase it by attacking targets of opportunity. In other words, they don't destroy stations, but they only target ships using raids instead of planned attacks.\n\nJedi are unique and their sectors cannot be conquered except through the plot.</t>
		<t id="2007">Threat Level</t>
		<t id="2008">Your threat level varies along the course of the game and depends on your actions. This is a crucial element of gameplay, as it affects many things. For instance, the strength of OCV and NPC fleets, the number of NPC shipyards, the amount of Sith and Pirate raids are all affected by your threat level.\n\nYou gain 1 Threat every 24 hour and when you conquer a sector. You lose 1 Threat when one of your sectors is captured or transferred to another race, but you do not lose any threat if it's abandoned.\n\nBeware of not being too greedy... If you conquer many sectors to increase your threat level without having proper defense, you will face very powerful OCV fleets. Thus, it is strongly recommended to NOT exceed Threat 5 before the first OCV invasion.\n\nThe time left before the next OCV invasion is displayed at the top of the Ministry of War screen.</t>
		<t id="2009">Marines: Boarding And Expeditions</t>
		<t id="2010">Mayhem completely overhauls the way you recruit marines, the way you board other ships and it also implements a new Expeditions feature. The first thing you'll notice is that you cannot recruit marines from Military Outposts anymore, you have to do it from your Sanctuaries through the Hangar Bay menu. It costs people, Disintegrator rifles and some credits as well. All your marines you recruit are rookies, meaning that they appear with low skills, but they have a few skill points that you can distribute by clicking on them in your Hangar Bay or in the Marines list available in the Personal console.\n\nThe skills of your marines are all useful. \033OEngineering\033X is used for cuting hulls, disabling cameras and opening safes. \033OHacking\033X is used for entering ships, stealing computer data and deactivating ship cores. Safes and computers can only be found in Expeditions. \033OMechanical\033X is only used for opening doors, but there are plenty of doors inside ships. \033OFighting\033X is used for calculating initiative, firing range \(low impact\) and movement speed.\n\nBoarding another ship is done through the Special command menu, or the contextual menu of the target. Note that some ships do not have this contextual menu, for an unknown reason. Instead of having to throw your marines into space or use a boarding pod, they teleport themselves directly to the point of entry, using the Transporter device of the ship that initiates the boarding operation. When such operation is launched, you can follow the progress of your team through the Boarding reports screen, available in the Personal console. Note that unlike the vanilla system, boarding takes a lot more time, so you better choose your target carefully.\n\nOnce inside another ship, your team of marines will have to get through multiple locations in order to access the ship core. For more information about combat, please see the Marines Equipment section.\n\nAt some point in the main story, you will unlock the Expeditions feature. Expeditions let you open rifts to distant galaxies from any of your Sanctuaries. Sending a team of marines through these rifts will launch an Expedition. They are similar to boarding operations, but generally have more enemies, more locations to explore, more loot, more enemies and a greater distance of shooting.\n\nIf you lose a boarding operation or an expedition, you can send another team of marines and the place - whether it's a ship or a rift - will be the same as you left it before. In other words, it doesn't get reset.\n\nOne of the main aspect of a boarding operation or an expedition is combat. Every ship and every rift is subdivided into multiple locations. Each of these locations has enemies inside. When your marines arrive, they have a chance to be spotted by the enemy. This chance is based on both initiative and the average score of all your marine fighting skills. If they are spotted, the enemy will ambush them and shoot them at optimal range. If they are not spotted, they will be able to move at their own optimal range, and then an initiative roll will define in which order every men will shoot. Once a location is clear, your marines will start searching for scraps, money, crystals and ship blueprints. See the marine equipment section for more details about combat.\n\nThe number of marines required to launch a boarding mission or an expedition depends on the ship class or the rift difficulty. For boarding operations, 20 marines are required for M2, 15 for M1, 12 for M7 and 8 for TM, TL and M6.</t>
		<t id="2011">Marines: Equipment</t>
		<t id="2012">One of the most important changes concerning marines is that each of them now have three pieces of equipment: cartridge, gear and weapon. These equipment have to be designed first, then crafted with Scraps, a new resource you can gather from boarding operations and expeditions.\n\n\033OCartridge\033X\nCaliber class: defines the base energy of a bullet, the base firing range, the size of the magazine, and also impacts the initiative score.\nMass factor: greatly impacts the bullet energy and the firing range.\nPenetration: impacts the bullet energy and defines the stopping power, which is the maximum damage that this cartridge can cause to the enemy health.\n\n\033OGear\033X\nProtection class: defines how much bullet energy the gear can stop.\nResistance: defines how many bullets this gear can stop per mission, ie. its durability. If it drops to 0 and if the protection is higher than the bullet energy, every bullet received will hit for 1 health damage. Note that this is a crucial statistic, as it indirectly increases the health of your marines. You should therefore prioritize it when equipping your marines. All bullets that hit a marine will reduce the resistance of his gear, whether it goes through or not.\nWeight: greatly impacts the initiative score.\n\n\033OWeapon\033X\nCaliber compatibility: every marine has to have the same caliber for both cartridge and weapon before going on a mission.\nHandling: impacts the initiative score \(compared to the gear weight stat, the effect is halved\).\nOptics: greatly impacts the firing range.\nPrecision: impacts both firing range and precision.\nQuality: impacts bullet energy, firing range and precision.\n\nEquipment can be retrieved by another team if the previous one has been totally killed. Note that you cannot bring reinforcements to a mission in progress.\n\n\033OPractical Guide\033X\nBegin by boarding TM class ships with default cartridges and weapons. To efficiently protect your marines, begin by boarding TMs as you upgrade from Republic Trooper Armor to Senate Commando Armor. Then work on upgrading from Blaster Pistols to Blaster Rifles. For boarding M7s, you'll want to upgrade your marines to Mandalorian armor as soon as possible. Sniper Rifles should be reserved only for Expeditions.</t>
		<t id="2013">Marines: Improvements</t>
		<t id="2014">Improvements can greatly increase the overall efficiency of your marines. They can be unlocked in your Research stations.\n\n\033ODeath commando\033X: reduces the Fighting skill of the enemies.\n\033OEasy action\033X: reduces the required difficulty to do actions like opening a door and hacking a network.\n\033OEquipment discount\033X: reduces the scrap costs of all equipment.\n\033OFast action\033X: reduces the time needed to do actions and to move from a location to another one. Highly recommended for boarding larger ships to reduce the chance they get destroyed by external forces during boarding.\n\033OFree marines\033X: removes the cost in credits of marines.\n\033OInitiative bonus\033X: increases the initiative of all your marines.\n\033OLucky spotters\033X: increases the chances of finding a safe or a computer in each room. Safes and computers can only be found in Expeditions.\n\033OReinforcements\033X: allows you to put more marines in your boarding and expedition squads. Does not affect the boarding squads sent to M6, TM and TL.\n\033OShield expertise\033X: allows you to board ships that have less than 50% shields instead of the 10% default limit.\n\033OSilent warriors\033X: reduces the risks of being ambushed when your marines enter a new room. Greatly reduces the deaths of your marines.\n\033OStealth team\033X: gives a chance to your marines to pass through enemies without alerting them. They can still search for safes, computers and scraps.</t>
		
		<!-- Miscellaneous -->
		<t id="3001">Loot And Bailing Rate</t>
		<t id="3002">Loot, aka FLC for Fight Loot Chance is a Litcube's Universe feature. However, in Mayhem, the FLC has a fix rate, making the loot more fun and useful in early-game. The FLC level that you can see in the Pilot Status screen should be ignored if you keep this feature on.\n\nBailing rates in Mayhem have been decreased a lot. I strongly recommend to keep it this way.\n\nBoth features are on by default and can be deactivated in the Artificial Life Settings screen, via the Gameplay menu.\n\nFreighters are special regarding loot. If they have a cargo and if any of your ships is the killer, they will always drop a part of it. Very useful for players who want to become pirates!</t>
		<t id="3003">Game Customization</t>
		<t id="3004">Many gameplay variables can be changed via a simple file located in X3/addon/t/9972-L044.xml. Almost everything can be adjusted to your taste! This file is often referenced as "the t-file".</t>
		<t id="3005">Other Gameplay Modifications</t>
		<t id="3006">Many things have been modified from vanilla game and Litcube's Universe. Maximum storage, universe map, scanners and satellites range, MK3 traders \(from MK3 Improvement Reloaded Reloaded\), agents, ship coloring options, prices, mining chances, satellite monitoring, fleets, and many other scripts.</t>
		<t id="3007">Victory</t>
		<t id="3008">Even though Mayhem is a sandbox, a certain victory can be achieved granting you special rewards. To achieve victory, you must complete one of the conditions listed in the Ministry of War menu, and you also need to finish the main plot.</t>
		<t id="3009">Personal Console</t>
		<t id="3010">The Player Console has been renamed, but also improved. You can reach most of the menus from here. Some are new, like the Satellite monitoring screen or the Sanctuaries list. You can also access a personal journal from here, where you can manage custom entries. Finally, you can teleport to any ship you own using this console. Note that doing so clears the previously set Homebase of the ship unless it is part of a Wing.</t>
		<t id="3011">Maintenance</t>
		<t id="3012">All ships cost money to maintain. If you do not have enough credits to pay the maintenance, ships will begin to frequently lose hull. You can self destruct any ship or OWP at any time through the Additional Ship Commands panel.\n\nMaintenance costs are influenced by the ship Quality. Quality is a value that you set in your Sanctuary. Lower quality levels decrease the ship costs, increase the maintenance, but also add a risk of engine, shield or laser temporary malfunction. You can see the Quality of each of your ship through the maintenance screen, via the Personal console. Docked ships are not affected by the risk of failure.</t>
		<t id="3013">Tips</t>
		<t id="3014">Mayhem is a sandbox. You decide what to do. If you want to be a peaceful trader, neglecting your empire, you can. If you prefer to be aggressive, making your own enemies and looting transporters, just attack them, but beware of consequences, because all factions are dynamic and react to what happens in their sectors.\n\n1/ If you start with a Sanctuary, you already have some wares you can sell in it, as well as your own weapons and shields. However, in early-game, you should start by exploring the universe and make sure that your people don't starve.\n\n2/ Ships can bail and drop their missiles, lasers and shields. If you or one of your ships is the killer, the chances are higher. Besides, destroying TS ships that transport cargo other than weapons always gives loot.\n\n3/ If your firepower is not high enough, start thinking of creating a satellite network. With the Satellite Monitoring tool \(Personal Console\), you can actually see where the wares are and, most importantly, the abandoned ships.\n\n4/ Many players have various playstyles. Some start by making miners or MK3 traders, others accomplish vanilla or company missions, and others prefer to focus on logistics and crafting. Being enemy with a particular faction can be very rewarding but also very dangerous. It's also a good way to make the game more combat oriented.\n\n5/ Repairing your ships at your Sanctuaries is a lot cheaper than going to a shipyard.\n\n6/ In early-game, scanning ships for data is crucial. Remember to scan the ships you capture, because selling them to a shipyard will not add their data to your database \(recycling them at your Sanctuaries, however, will add them\). You can also put yourself into the middle of a battle opposing two other factions and try to scan unshielded ships. Note that there's an Additional ship command that automatically adds ship data to your research database.\n\n7/ OCV should be your main concern in early game. Try to keep your Threat at 3 if you are a new player. At this level, you should make it with only a handful of M3 and two or three M6. Consider building an OWP if your threat is higher, as the OCV tend to target them in priority.\n\n8/ Red, Yellow, Blue, Green and Black Crystals are needed for buying equipment at your Sanctuaries. You can buy them at Mining posts or mine them directly yourself. If you mine them, you can use a Mobile mining base \(a TL\) and a Courier to transfer crystals back to your Sanctuaries. You can also transmute your crystals with an expensive Crystal Transmuter, only craftable in your Sanctuaries.\n\n9/ Miners are very lucrative, but make sure to defend them, you never know who may hunt them down...\n\n10/ Pay attention to borders. If a faction sector is adjacent to a Sith territory, it's very likely that some combat will occur, with loot and abandoned ships. The same goes for two factions in war.\n\n11/ If you struggle to scan ship data, especially M6, M7 and above, consider buying an access to a Ship data market of a race you have good reputation with \(Ministry of War\).\n\n12/ Specialize your sectors! It will make the management of your Dock Agents and the maintenance of your empire easier.\n\n13/ Remember that the more people you have in a Sanctuary, the faster it is at building ships. Check sectors stats and establish your ship hangar where the maximum population is high.\n\n14/ Don't waste your time looking for the right Equipment Dock to sell your stuff; pack it into a cheap ship, like a TP, then sell the whole package to a Shipyard!\n\n15/ Boarding TM ships is the best way to train your marines and get some precious Scraps.\n\n16/ Avoid excessive intermediaries. It's better to export directly from your factories instead of going through an intermediary Sanctuary.</t>
		<t id="3015">Repair Ships And Stations</t>
		<t id="3016">All ships that can have marines onboard can order them to repair any ship or station. The repair process can take a long time, as it is influenced by the skills of each marine. A damage on a ship can be of three types, according to its hull integrity: structural \(&lt;= 33%\), internal \(&lt;= 66%\) and mechanical \(&lt; 100%\). These three types of damage are associated to one skill, respectively Engineering, Hacking and Mechanical. Structural damages take longer to repair than internal ones, and internal damages take longer to repair than mechanical ones.\n\nThe "Repair ship or station" command is only available to ships equipped with a Special Command Software. Obviously, they also need to be able to load marines.</t>
		<t id="3017">Ascension</t>
		<t id="3018">Through the Personal console, you can access your current Ascension progress. Ascension provides dynamic achievements over 5 levels. Each achievement must be completed within a time frame. If you miss the deadline, you lose your Ascension, but you will be able to restart a new one at a cost of 1 Threat. If you manage to succeed in all the 5 levels, you will be able to choose a special reward. This reward is non-essential and shouldn't be your top priority. However, following the Ascension sometimes force you to rethink your early strategy.</t>
		<t id="3019">Local Merchants And Trading Stations</t>
		<t id="3020">Most sectors have a Trading station, but in Mayhem, they are all empty. That's because Mayhem overhauls the Bartering system \(now called 'Local Merchants'\) and offers you a new way to buy and sell crafting resources. You can consult a list of all Local merchants in your Personal console. Note that only the merchants from Trading stations are displayed by default. To display the merchants of the other stations, you first need to visit these stations.</t>	
		<t id="3021">Crystal Transmutation</t>
		<t id="3022">The Crystal Transmuter is a new equipment that allows you to transform any crystal \(included the one you build in Crystal Fabs\) to a higher quality version of it. Crystals turn into Red Crystals, Red Crystals into Yellow, Yellow into Blue, Blue into Green and Green into Black. Using this equipment costs shield energy.</t>
		<t id="3023">Fleets</t>
		<t id="3024">Mayhem totally overhauls how fleets work, and fixed a lot of vanilla bugs and weird mechanics. Be sure to read the help panel of each command in the Fleet submenu to have a clear understanding of their function. Fleet ships resupply to each other and repair to the nearest Sanctuary before any regroup order, frequently given by the leader during most actions, and also during a Call To Arms. Homebase and turrets are automatically set for each ship of the fleet. Don't forget that you can filter Fleet commanders in your Property Owned screen and also that you can broadcast an order to all the fleet ships at any time.</t>
		<t id="3025">Backlog</t>
		<t id="3026">In your Personal console, you will find a very powerful way to build your ships: the Backlog. From here, you can queue all your laser, shield, missile and ship projects, but most importantly, you can build full templates in a single click. Note that if the next project in the queue cannot be built for lack of resources, each other project in the list will be considered. In other words, the production won't just stall if something else is buildable.</t>
		<t id="3027">Random Galaxy Connections</t>
		<t id="3028">When you start a new game, a few Trans-Orbital gates are randomly built around the galaxy. These gates are un-jumpable and the connections they add between two sectors are hidden on the galaxy map.</t>
		<t id="3029">Become A Taxi</t>
		<t id="3030">Via your Personal console, you can register and unregister your current ship as a taxi. When you are a taxi, you have a chance of getting a few passengers onboard when you dock at any station. You will be notified of how many of them got in your ship, but their destination is only displayed in their passenger info panel, accessible from your Freight Bay screen. With higher faction reputation, you'll get more clients who are willing to go further. With higher trade rank, you'll receive higher payment. This feature replaces the vanilla taxi missions.</t>
		<t id="3031">Used Ships</t>
		<t id="3032">Companies don't have much activity in the galaxy, but they have salvagers who collect abandoned wares and ships. When a ship is captured by a salvager, it is sent to a nearby station where it will be sold as a used ship. You can then buy these used ships from the Companies screen in the Ministry of War menu. This feature replaces the used ship vanilla missions.</t>
		<t id="3033">Known Issues</t>
		<t id="3034">- When you claim an abandoned ship, or buy a used ship, the ships that were hostile to its previous owner will sometimes turn against you, even if they're your friends.\n- Ships created by the mission vanilla system sometimes receive more engine tunings that they're supposed to, resulting in extraordinary speed.\n- Some rare ships are invulnerable. However, there is a script that make them jump out of existence whenever a ship has 0 hull and is not destroyed.\n- Some ships will sometimes stop patrolling or defending a sector after being attacked. However, most of them are recalled after a while.\n- Wings are unmodified, which leads to various bugs, especially one that makes them stuck on their current command and accept no others until you manually order a 'None' command.</t>
		<t id="3035">Game Difficulty</t>
		<t id="3036">The difficulty setting affects OCV invasions, maintenance costs, Pirate and Sith additional invasions, Research cycles, loot chances, bailing chances and number of Scraps per boarding operation. Some changes take some time to apply if not done at game start.</t>
		<t id="3037">Autopopulate</t>
		<t id="3038">Autopopulate is the name of the feature that makes each sector builds their own stations until the maximum support is reached. Generally, it will try to build stations that produce the resources needed by other stations in the area. Otherwise, it will build a random station, favoring the ones that produce crafting products, such as Microchips and Computer Components. It will not build any mines.</t>
		<t id="3039">Easy Economy</t>
		<t id="3040">Through your Personal console, you can activate Easy Economy. This option reduces the number of resource types you require to do all the crafting. With this option on, ships require Computer Components and Quantum Tubes; stations Ore and Teladianium; shields and lasers require Crystals, and missiles Silicon Wafers. Note that the costs are adjusted. This option can be activated and deactivated at any time, although it drastically changes the way you manage your logistics.</t>

	</page>

</language>